<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Latest Cryptocurrency Price News, Predictions &amp; Updates from Blockonomi</title>
	<atom:link href="https://blockonomi.com/analysis/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://blockonomi.com/analysis/</link>
	<description>Cryptocurrency News &#38; Your Guide to the Blockchain Economy</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 11:37:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.7.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/fav-50x50.png</url>
	<title>Latest Cryptocurrency Price News, Predictions &amp; Updates from Blockonomi</title>
	<link>https://blockonomi.com/analysis/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">134176212</site>	<item>
		<title>Chainlink (LINK) Price Analysis: December Correction Tests Market Resolve</title>
		<link>https://blockonomi.com/chainlink-link-price-analysis-december-correction-tests-market-resolve/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oliver Dale]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 11:37:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Analysis]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blockonomi.com/?p=108767</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>TLDR Chainlink (LINK) has experienced a sharp 15% price correction after a strong December rally, currently trading at $24.08 Despite the recent downturn, analysts maintain bullish predictions for a $35 price target in January 2025, supported by Trump&#8217;s election victory and pro-crypto sentiment The token has shown impressive growth with a 63% increase over 30 [...]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blockonomi.com/chainlink-link-price-analysis-december-correction-tests-market-resolve/">Chainlink (LINK) Price Analysis: December Correction Tests Market Resolve</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blockonomi.com">Blockonomi</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>TLDR</h2>
<ul>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Chainlink (LINK) has experienced a sharp 15% price correction after a strong December rally, currently trading at $24.08</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Despite the recent downturn, analysts maintain bullish predictions for a $35 price target in January 2025, supported by Trump&#8217;s election victory and pro-crypto sentiment</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">The token has shown impressive growth with a 63% increase over 30 days and 69% over the past year</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Technical analyst Ali Martinez identified a &#8220;buy signal&#8221; on LINK&#8217;s four-hour chart, though the asset failed to maintain its $26.8 support level</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">CoinCodex predicts LINK could reach $75 by May 2025, settling around $45 for the year</li>
</ul>
<hr />
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The cryptocurrency market has witnessed an unexpected shift as <a href="https://watcher.guru/news/chainlink-falls-15-why-analysts-still-expect-link-to-hit-35-in-january">Chainlink (LINK) undergoes a notable price correction, dropping 15% from its recent highs.</a> The digital asset, which had been riding high during December&#8217;s crypto rally, is now trading at $24.08, prompting renewed analysis of its short-term trajectory.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Trading data from CoinMarketCap reveals LINK has experienced a 14.97% decline over the past seven days, with an 11% drop occurring within a 24-hour period. This movement represents a sharp reversal from the asset&#8217;s previously strong performance, which saw gains of 63% over the past month.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The correction comes amid broader market movements following Donald Trump&#8217;s victory in the 2024 US presidential election. While Bitcoin has reached unprecedented six-figure values, LINK&#8217;s recent performance has diverged from the general market trend, catching many traders off guard.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Market watchers have noted a substantial increase in LINK&#8217;s trading volume, which surged 49% on Thursday. This spike in activity suggests heightened investor interest despite the price decline, potentially indicating a period of price discovery and market repositioning.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Technical indicators have begun to show promising signs for LINK&#8217;s recovery. Cryptocurrency analyst Ali Martinez recently highlighted a buy signal appearing on the asset&#8217;s four-hour chart. While the token failed to maintain its critical $26.8 support level, this technical indicator suggests potential upward momentum.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">The TD Sequential indicator has flashed a buy signal on the <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Chainlink?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Chainlink</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%24LINK&amp;src=ctag&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">$LINK</a> 4-hour chart. If the key $26.8 support holds, <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/LINK?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#LINK</a> could aim for a rebound toward $28.5 or even $30.2. <a href="https://t.co/4HaaTSVygf">pic.twitter.com/4HaaTSVygf</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Ali (@ali_charts) <a href="https://twitter.com/ali_charts/status/1869340079933583550?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 18, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Historical data shows LINK&#8217;s yearly performance remains impressive, with a 69% increase over the past twelve months. This longer-term trend has maintained investor confidence despite the current price correction, as it demonstrates the asset&#8217;s capacity for sustained growth.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Price prediction platform CoinCodex has maintained its bullish stance on LINK&#8217;s prospects for early 2025. Their analysis suggests the asset could reach $40 in January, citing the anticipated impact of the incoming administration&#8217;s pro-cryptocurrency policies.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The platform&#8217;s data indicates even stronger potential for growth as 2025 progresses. May 2025 stands out as a particularly optimistic target, with predictions pointing to a possible $75 price level. This would represent a substantial increase from current valuations.</p>
<figure id="attachment_108768" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-108768" style="width: 847px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-108768" src="https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-11-35-15-Chainlink-Price-LINK-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko.png" alt="Chainlink Price on CoinGecko" width="847" height="628" srcset="https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-11-35-15-Chainlink-Price-LINK-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko.png 847w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-11-35-15-Chainlink-Price-LINK-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-300x222.png 300w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-11-35-15-Chainlink-Price-LINK-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-768x569.png 768w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-11-35-15-Chainlink-Price-LINK-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-50x37.png 50w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-11-35-15-Chainlink-Price-LINK-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-150x111.png 150w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-11-35-15-Chainlink-Price-LINK-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-450x334.png 450w" sizes="(max-width: 847px) 100vw, 847px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-108768" class="wp-caption-text">Chainlink Price on <a href="https://www.coingecko.com/en/coins/chainlink">CoinGecko</a></figcaption></figure>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Trading patterns show LINK&#8217;s recent correction has not fundamentally altered its market structure. The asset continues to maintain price levels well above its early 2024 valuations, suggesting the current downturn may be temporary rather than indicative of a longer-term trend reversal.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Market data indicates LINK&#8217;s correlation with other major cryptocurrencies has remained relatively stable during this correction. This suggests the asset&#8217;s price movement is more likely tied to token-specific factors rather than broader market sentiment.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The asset&#8217;s performance relative to other alternative cryptocurrencies remains noteworthy. LINK has outperformed several peers in the same market cap range, including VeChain (VET), Stellar (XLM), and Tron (TRX), when measuring year-to-date returns.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Technical analysis of LINK&#8217;s trading patterns reveals several key support levels below the current price. These levels could provide stabilization points if the correction continues, potentially preventing further substantial declines.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Volume analysis shows increased activity at key price levels, suggesting active price discovery. This heightened trading activity often precedes major price movements, though the direction remains uncertain.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">CoinCodex&#8217;s analysis suggests LINK could stabilize around $45 throughout 2025, representing a 120% increase from current levels. This prediction accounts for various market factors, including regulatory developments and broader cryptocurrency adoption trends.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The most recent data shows LINK trading volumes have begun to normalize after Thursday&#8217;s spike, with price action showing early signs of stabilization around the $24 level.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blockonomi.com/chainlink-link-price-analysis-december-correction-tests-market-resolve/">Chainlink (LINK) Price Analysis: December Correction Tests Market Resolve</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blockonomi.com">Blockonomi</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">108767</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ethereum (ETH) Price Update: Price Action Suggests Bearish Momentum Below $3,650</title>
		<link>https://blockonomi.com/ethereum-eth-price-update-price-action-suggests-bearish-momentum-below-3650/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oliver Dale]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 10:23:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ethereum]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blockonomi.com/?p=108753</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>TLDR Ethereum has experienced a sharp decline, dropping below $3,680 and currently trading under $3,550 A key bearish trend line has formed with resistance at $3,650 on the hourly chart The cryptocurrency reached a low of $3,324, with current major support at $3,320 Technical indicators, including MACD and RSI, suggest continued bearish momentum Recovery would [...]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blockonomi.com/ethereum-eth-price-update-price-action-suggests-bearish-momentum-below-3650/">Ethereum (ETH) Price Update: Price Action Suggests Bearish Momentum Below $3,650</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blockonomi.com">Blockonomi</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>TLDR</h2>
<ul>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Ethereum has experienced a sharp decline, dropping below $3,680 and currently trading under $3,550</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">A key bearish trend line has formed with resistance at $3,650 on the hourly chart</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">The cryptocurrency reached a low of $3,324, with current major support at $3,320</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Technical indicators, including MACD and RSI, suggest continued bearish momentum</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Recovery would require breaking through multiple resistance levels, with $3,715 being a crucial point</li>
</ul>
<hr />
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Ethereum&#8217;s price trajectory has taken a downward turn, with the leading altcoin dropping below several key support levels in recent hours. <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/analysis/eth/ethereum-price-plunge-3320/">The cryptocurrency has fallen more than 7% and is currently trading below the $3,550 mark, showing continued bearish pressure in the short term.</a></p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The decline began as Ethereum struggled to maintain momentum above the $3,680 level, leading to a cascade of technical support breaks. The price action mirrors the broader market movement, with Bitcoin also experiencing similar downward pressure during the same period.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Trading data from Kraken shows that Ethereum&#8217;s price movement has broken below the 100-hourly Simple Moving Average, a technical indicator often used to determine market trends. This break suggests that bears have gained control of the immediate price action.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The depth of the current decline became apparent as Ethereum&#8217;s price continued to slide, eventually reaching a local low of $3,324. This price point represents a notable departure from recent trading ranges and has established a new support level that traders are watching closely.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Technical analysis of the hourly chart reveals the formation of a bearish trend line with resistance positioned at $3,650. This pattern suggests that any attempted recovery will face strong selling pressure at these higher levels.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Current market data indicates that <a href="https://moneycheck.com/best-ethereum-casinos/">Ethereum</a> is consolidating around the $3,510 level, which coincides with the 23.6% Fibonacci retracement level. This technical measure takes into account the recent price swing from $4,105 to the low of $3,324.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">For traders looking at potential recovery scenarios, the first major hurdle appears at the $3,650 mark. This level is reinforced by the previously mentioned bearish trend line, making it a crucial point for any potential upward movement.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">A more substantial resistance level has formed near $3,715, which represents the 50% Fibonacci retracement level of the recent downward movement. This price point could prove to be a key battleground between bulls and bears in the coming trading sessions.</p>
<figure id="attachment_108754" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-108754" style="width: 847px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-108754" src="https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-10-20-45-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko.png" alt="Ethereum Price on CoinGecko" width="847" height="625" srcset="https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-10-20-45-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko.png 847w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-10-20-45-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-300x221.png 300w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-10-20-45-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-768x567.png 768w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-10-20-45-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-50x37.png 50w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-10-20-45-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-150x111.png 150w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-10-20-45-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-450x332.png 450w" sizes="(max-width: 847px) 100vw, 847px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-108754" class="wp-caption-text">Ethereum Price on <a href="https://www.coingecko.com/en/coins/ethereum">CoinGecko</a></figcaption></figure>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Should buyers manage to push the price above these immediate resistance levels, the next major target would be the $3,800 mark. A successful break above this point could open the path toward the psychologically important $4,000 level.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">However, the current technical setup suggests that downside risks remain prevalent. The immediate support level to watch is near $3,350, with a more substantial support zone established around $3,320.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">If selling pressure continues and Ethereum fails to hold these support levels, the next potential landing zones appear at $3,250 and $3,150. Technical traders are particularly watching the $3,050 level as a crucial support point that could come into play if the current bearish momentum persists.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The hourly MACD (Moving Average Convergence Divergence) indicator is showing increasing momentum in the bearish zone, adding weight to the negative short-term outlook. This technical indicator is often used to measure trend strength and direction.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Similarly, the RSI (Relative Strength Index) for ETH/USD has dropped below the 50 zone, suggesting that bearish pressure currently dominates the market sentiment. The RSI is a momentum indicator that helps traders identify overbought or oversold conditions.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Trading volume data indicates increased selling activity during this price decline, with multiple large transactions recorded as the price broke through various support levels.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The price action has created a series of lower highs and lower lows on the hourly chart, a pattern that typically indicates a continuing downward trend in technical analysis.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Market data shows that order books are currently weighted toward the sell side, with substantial resistance building up near the $3,650 level.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Recent price action has led to the liquidation of multiple long positions, contributing to the downward pressure as forced selling triggers additional price declines.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Hourly chart patterns suggest the formation of a bearish flag, indicating that the current consolidation might be temporary before another potential move lower.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blockonomi.com/ethereum-eth-price-update-price-action-suggests-bearish-momentum-below-3650/">Ethereum (ETH) Price Update: Price Action Suggests Bearish Momentum Below $3,650</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blockonomi.com">Blockonomi</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">108753</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>XRP Price Analysis: Support Builds as Trading Activity Increases</title>
		<link>https://blockonomi.com/xrp-price-analysis-support-builds-as-trading-activity-increases/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oliver Dale]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 10:16:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Analysis]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blockonomi.com/?p=108750</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>TLDR XRP has gained nearly 5% in 24 hours, trading at $2.21 with strong support Bollinger Bands indicator suggests potential 490% price increase based on historical patterns Analysts project possible rise to $10.82, surpassing previous $3.40 all-time high Technical analysis indicates key resistance levels at $2.42 and $2.92 Price movement coincides with potential regulatory changes [...]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blockonomi.com/xrp-price-analysis-support-builds-as-trading-activity-increases/">XRP Price Analysis: Support Builds as Trading Activity Increases</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blockonomi.com">Blockonomi</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>TLDR</h2>
<ul>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">XRP has gained nearly 5% in 24 hours, trading at $2.21 with strong support</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Bollinger Bands indicator suggests potential 490% price increase based on historical patterns</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Analysts project possible rise to $10.82, surpassing previous $3.40 all-time high</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Technical analysis indicates key resistance levels at $2.42 and $2.92</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Price movement coincides with potential regulatory changes under new administration</li>
</ul>
<hr />
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The cryptocurrency XRP has demonstrated notable price stability and upward movement in recent market conditions, maintaining its position above $2.20 despite broader market corrections affecting other major cryptocurrencies.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words"><a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/xrp-news/xrp-price-readies-for-record-breaking-peaks-as-bollinger-bands-signal-490-upswing/">Trading data shows XRP has recorded a nearly 5% increase over the past 24 hours,</a> while market leaders Bitcoin and Ethereum experienced declines of 2.2% and 4.6% respectively. This divergence from the general market trend has caught the attention of technical analysts and traders.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The current price action comes as XRP maintains strong support levels just below its trading price of $2.21. Market data indicates steady buying pressure at these levels, suggesting a solid foundation for potential future price movements.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Technical analysis of XRP&#8217;s price charts reveals interesting patterns, particularly in the Bollinger Bands indicator on the 12-hour timeframe. This volatility measurement tool shows a notable tightening pattern, similar to formations observed before previous price increases.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Analyst Steph, known for cryptocurrency technical analysis, has drawn attention to historical similarities in XRP&#8217;s Bollinger Band patterns. According to their research, the last time such a pattern emerged, XRP&#8217;s price experienced a 490% increase. If this pattern were to repeat, it could push XRP&#8217;s price toward $10.82.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The trading volume for XRP has remained steady during this period, with consistent activity across major exchanges. This stability in trading volume adds weight to the current price levels and suggests genuine market interest rather than temporary speculation.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Looking at key price levels, the $2.42 mark has emerged as an important resistance point. Technical analyst DarkDefender identifies this as a crucial level that XRP needs to break through before testing higher targets. Beyond this, $2.92 represents another key resistance level that could influence future price movement.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Historical data shows XRP&#8217;s previous all-time high stands at $3.40, reached in January 2018. The current market structure suggests potential for testing these levels, according to multiple technical analyses. Trading patterns indicate increasing buyer interest at current prices.</p>
<figure id="attachment_108751" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-108751" style="width: 847px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-108751" src="https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-09-17-46-XRP-Price-XRP-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-1.png" alt="XRP Price on CoinGecko" width="847" height="630" srcset="https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-09-17-46-XRP-Price-XRP-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-1.png 847w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-09-17-46-XRP-Price-XRP-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-1-300x223.png 300w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-09-17-46-XRP-Price-XRP-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-1-768x571.png 768w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-09-17-46-XRP-Price-XRP-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-1-50x37.png 50w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-09-17-46-XRP-Price-XRP-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-1-150x112.png 150w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-09-17-46-XRP-Price-XRP-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-1-450x335.png 450w" sizes="(max-width: 847px) 100vw, 847px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-108751" class="wp-caption-text">XRP Price on <a href="https://www.coingecko.com/en/coins/xrp">CoinGecko</a></figcaption></figure>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Market participants have noted XRP&#8217;s ability to maintain price stability during broader market corrections. This relative strength has contributed to growing interest from traders looking for assets that can withstand market volatility.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The daily price chart shows multiple tests of support levels, with buyers stepping in consistently around the $2.20 mark. This price action has created a series of higher lows on the chart, typically considered a bullish pattern in technical analysis.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Another analyst, Javon, has examined <a href="https://moneycheck.com/best-ethereum-casinos/">XRP</a>&#8216;s previous bull market cycles. Their analysis suggests that if XRP follows similar patterns to its last full bull cycle, which saw a 600% increase, current prices could multiply several times over.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Trading data shows increased activity around key price levels, particularly near the $2.42 resistance point. This concentration of trading activity often indicates important technical levels that traders watch closely.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The current market structure shows XRP trading above several moving averages, typically considered a positive technical indicator. These moving averages have provided support during recent price pullbacks.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Price action on lower timeframes indicates steady accumulation, with buyers absorbing selling pressure at current levels. This behavior often precedes larger price movements, according to technical analysis principles.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Recent trading sessions have shown increased market participation during Asian trading hours, suggesting growing interest from markets in that region. This geographic diversification of trading activity can contribute to price stability.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The latest data shows XRP maintaining its position above $2.20, with steady trading volume and consistent buyer interest at current levels. Technical indicators continue to suggest potential for upward price movement, while support levels remain firm.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blockonomi.com/xrp-price-analysis-support-builds-as-trading-activity-increases/">XRP Price Analysis: Support Builds as Trading Activity Increases</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blockonomi.com">Blockonomi</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">108750</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dogecoin ($DOGE) Price: Plunges 35% from 2024 Peak as Fed Policy Shifts Market Sentiment</title>
		<link>https://blockonomi.com/dogecoin-doge-price-plunges-35-from-2024-peak-as-fed-policy-shifts-market-sentiment/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oliver Dale]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 09:53:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Memes]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blockonomi.com/?p=108717</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>TLDR DOGE dropped 12.4% in 24 hours following Fed Chair Powell&#8217;s hawkish comments, falling to $0.31 from a 2024 high of $0.47 Trading volume surged 67% to $10.25 billion as holders repositioned their investments Major outflows observed on Binance ($83 million) with trading volume spiking 74% to $1.85 billion Other meme coins followed the decline, [...]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blockonomi.com/dogecoin-doge-price-plunges-35-from-2024-peak-as-fed-policy-shifts-market-sentiment/">Dogecoin ($DOGE) Price: Plunges 35% from 2024 Peak as Fed Policy Shifts Market Sentiment</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blockonomi.com">Blockonomi</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>TLDR</h2>
<ul>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">DOGE dropped 12.4% in 24 hours following Fed Chair Powell&#8217;s hawkish comments, falling to $0.31 from a 2024 high of $0.47</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Trading volume surged 67% to $10.25 billion as holders repositioned their investments</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Major outflows observed on Binance ($83 million) with trading volume spiking 74% to $1.85 billion</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Other meme coins followed the decline, with Shiba Inu down 23.3% and BONK falling 22.5%</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Despite the correction, DOGE maintains its position as the seventh-largest crypto with $46.6 billion market cap</li>
</ul>
<hr />
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words"><a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/analysis/doge/dogecoin-doge-plummets-30/">Dogecoin (DOGE) experienced a sharp decline in the past 24 hours, dropping 12.4% to $0.31</a> as markets processed the Federal Reserve&#8217;s latest economic outlook. The popular meme coin&#8217;s descent coincides with broader market turbulence following Fed Chair Jerome Powell&#8217;s comments about inflation projections.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Trading volume for DOGE surged 67% to $10.25 billion as investors rushed to adjust their positions. The current price represents a 35% decrease from its 2024 high of $0.47, marking one of the largest corrections for the asset this year.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Binance, the largest cryptocurrency exchange by volume, reported substantial outflows exceeding $83 million. <a href="https://decrypt.co/298070/dogecoin-meme-coins-fall-as-fed-fears-linger">The platform&#8217;s DOGE trading volume increased by 74% to $1.85 billion,</a> according to data from CoinGlass. The numbers suggest a coordinated move by holders to reduce their exposure.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The price action follows Powell&#8217;s remarks that recent inflation data had &#8220;fallen apart,&#8221; triggering concerns about the central bank&#8217;s monetary policy path. The Fed&#8217;s indication of maintaining higher interest rates for an extended period has particularly impacted speculative assets.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Market data reveals concentrated selling pressure across major exchanges, with negative net flows dominating the trading activity. Only Bybit and Bitstamp showed positive inflows, indicating a broader market exodus rather than exchange-specific events.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Exchange-wide patterns show persistent selling from late November through December. The DOGE/USDT trading pair on major platforms like Binance and OKX has declined approximately 23% over the past week.</p>
<figure id="attachment_108725" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-108725" style="width: 847px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-108725" src="https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-09-48-50-Dogecoin-Price-DOGE-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko.png" alt="Dogecoin Price on CoinGecko" width="847" height="623" srcset="https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-09-48-50-Dogecoin-Price-DOGE-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko.png 847w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-09-48-50-Dogecoin-Price-DOGE-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-300x221.png 300w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-09-48-50-Dogecoin-Price-DOGE-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-768x565.png 768w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-09-48-50-Dogecoin-Price-DOGE-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-50x37.png 50w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-09-48-50-Dogecoin-Price-DOGE-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-150x110.png 150w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-09-48-50-Dogecoin-Price-DOGE-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-450x331.png 450w" sizes="(max-width: 847px) 100vw, 847px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-108725" class="wp-caption-text">Dogecoin Price on <a href="https://www.coingecko.com/en/coins/dogecoin">CoinGecko</a></figcaption></figure>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The cryptocurrency&#8217;s current market capitalization stands at $46.6 billion, allowing it to maintain its position as the seventh-largest cryptocurrency by market value. This metric highlights DOGE&#8217;s continued importance in the broader crypto ecosystem despite the recent price action.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Other meme coins have followed <a href="https://moneycheck.com/best-doge-casinos/">DOGE&#8217;s</a> downward trajectory. <a href="https://moneycheck.com/best-shib-casinos/">Shiba Inu (SHIB)</a> dropped 23.3% during the same period, while BONK experienced a 22.5% decline. The parallel movements suggest market-wide pressure on the meme coin sector.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Recent Solana-based meme coins have also faced challenges. MOODENG and CHILLGUY saw their values drop by 38% and 43% respectively. Peanut the Squirrel (PNUT) declined 46%, though it maintains a market cap above $672 million.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The exception to the downward trend has been Fartcoin, which gained 71% over the past week and shows a 323% increase for the month. The token&#8217;s performance stands out against the broader market decline, attracting mainstream media attention including coverage on CBS&#8217; The Late Show with Stephen Colbert.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Trading data from major exchanges indicates heightened volatility in DOGE markets. The 24-hour trading range has widened considerably, with prices testing several support levels before finding temporary stability.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Technical indicators show increased selling pressure across multiple timeframes. The hourly charts display a series of lower highs and lower lows, suggesting bears currently control market momentum.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Bitcoin&#8217;s simultaneous retreat below $100,000 has amplified pressure on alternative cryptocurrencies. However, data shows meme coins have experienced steeper percentage drops compared to mainstream digital assets.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Historical price data puts the current situation in perspective. While DOGE trades 57% below its all-time high of $0.73 reached during the 2021 bull market, current prices still represent a massive increase from its initial valuation.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The latest market data from CoinGlass shows liquidation cascades across major exchanges, with long positions bearing the brunt of the selling pressure. This pattern suggests leveraged traders faced particular challenges during the recent price action.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blockonomi.com/dogecoin-doge-price-plunges-35-from-2024-peak-as-fed-policy-shifts-market-sentiment/">Dogecoin ($DOGE) Price: Plunges 35% from 2024 Peak as Fed Policy Shifts Market Sentiment</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blockonomi.com">Blockonomi</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">108717</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Solana (SOL) Price: Solana (SOL) Holds $210 Support as Network Activity Hits New Heights</title>
		<link>https://blockonomi.com/solana-sol-price-solana-sol-holds-210-support-as-network-activity-hits-new-heights/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oliver Dale]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 09:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Analysis]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blockonomi.com/?p=108706</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>TLDR Solana has maintained stability at $210 support level despite a 7% drop following Federal Reserve&#8217;s rate decision, showing strong market resilience Network activity is reaching record levels with nearly 67 million daily transactions, indicating robust user adoption and platform growth Technical analysis shows SOL trading within a falling wedge pattern while holding monthly and [...]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blockonomi.com/solana-sol-price-solana-sol-holds-210-support-as-network-activity-hits-new-heights/">Solana (SOL) Price: Solana (SOL) Holds $210 Support as Network Activity Hits New Heights</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blockonomi.com">Blockonomi</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>TLDR</h2>
<ul>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Solana has maintained stability at $210 support level despite a 7% drop following Federal Reserve&#8217;s rate decision, showing strong market resilience</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Network activity is reaching record levels with nearly 67 million daily transactions, indicating robust user adoption and platform growth</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Technical analysis shows SOL trading within a falling wedge pattern while holding monthly and weekly support levels, suggesting a potential breakout</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Key resistance levels at $225 and $240 need to be broken for confirmation of bullish momentum</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">On-chain metrics and sustained network usage provide fundamental support for potential price appreciation</li>
</ul>
<hr />
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The Solana blockchain continues to demonstrate market resilience, maintaining its position above the $210 support level despite experiencing a 7% price decline following the Federal Reserve&#8217;s recent monetary policy announcement. The Fed&#8217;s decision to implement a 25 basis point rate cut, coupled with projections of fewer rate cuts for 2024, triggered immediate market reactions across the cryptocurrency sector.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">On-chain data reveals that Solana&#8217;s network activity has reached unprecedented levels, with daily transactions approaching 67 million. This metric showcases the platform&#8217;s growing adoption and continued utility, even amid broader market volatility. The sustained transaction volume positions Solana among the most actively used blockchain networks in the ecosystem.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Technical analysis from market expert Jelle indicates that Solana has successfully defended its monthly and weekly support levels. The asset continues to trade within a falling wedge pattern, a formation that traditionally precedes upward price movement. This technical structure, combined with strong network fundamentals, provides a foundation for potential price appreciation.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr"><a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%24SOL&amp;src=ctag&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">$SOL</a> took out the lows, held monthly &amp; weekly support &#8212; and stayed inside the falling wedge.</p>
<p>Eyes on a breakout next &#8211; targeting new all-time highs. <a href="https://t.co/JcvsoXNdFi">pic.twitter.com/JcvsoXNdFi</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Jelle (@CryptoJelleNL) <a href="https://twitter.com/CryptoJelleNL/status/1869638913301893443?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 19, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The $210 price level has emerged as a crucial support zone, with buyers consistently stepping in to defend this threshold. Market data shows substantial bid pressure at this level, suggesting that investors view this price point as an attractive entry opportunity. The persistence of this support level, particularly during periods of market stress, underscores the market&#8217;s confidence in Solana&#8217;s value proposition.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Looking at higher timeframes, <a href="https://moneycheck.com/best-solana-casinos/">Solana</a> faces key resistance levels at $225 and $240. Breaking above these thresholds could trigger renewed buying interest and potentially lead to an acceleration of upward momentum. Trading volumes at these price points will be crucial in determining the strength of any potential breakout.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Network metrics continue to paint a positive picture for Solana&#8217;s ecosystem growth. The platform&#8217;s ability to process nearly 67 million daily transactions without compromising performance demonstrates the scalability advantages that initially attracted developers and users to the network. This sustained activity level suggests that the network&#8217;s utility extends beyond speculative trading.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Market analysts point to the combination of technical and fundamental factors as potential catalysts for price action. The convergence of strong network metrics with favorable technical patterns often precedes periods of price discovery. However, broader market conditions and macroeconomic factors continue to influence short-term price movements.</p>
<figure id="attachment_108707" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-108707" style="width: 847px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-108707" src="https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-09-34-46-Solana-Price-SOL-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko.png" alt="Solana Price on CoinGecko" width="847" height="635" srcset="https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-09-34-46-Solana-Price-SOL-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko.png 847w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-09-34-46-Solana-Price-SOL-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-300x225.png 300w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-09-34-46-Solana-Price-SOL-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-768x576.png 768w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-09-34-46-Solana-Price-SOL-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-50x37.png 50w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-09-34-46-Solana-Price-SOL-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-150x112.png 150w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-09-34-46-Solana-Price-SOL-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-450x337.png 450w" sizes="(max-width: 847px) 100vw, 847px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-108707" class="wp-caption-text">Solana Price on <a href="https://www.coingecko.com/en/coins/solana">CoinGecko</a></figcaption></figure>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Recent developments in the Solana ecosystem have contributed to the network&#8217;s growing adoption. The platform has seen an increase in decentralized application (dApp) activity, with various protocols launching or expanding their services on the network. This organic ecosystem growth supports the narrative of Solana&#8217;s long-term value proposition.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The Federal Reserve&#8217;s policy decisions continue to impact cryptocurrency markets, including Solana. The recent announcement of fewer projected rate cuts for 2024 led to immediate price reactions across the sector. However, Solana&#8217;s ability to maintain support levels during this period of uncertainty highlights the asset&#8217;s market maturity.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Trading volumes across major exchanges show balanced activity, with neither buyers nor sellers dominating the order books. This equilibrium suggests that the market is consolidating at current levels, potentially building a base for future price movement. The stability in trading volumes also indicates sustained market interest in the asset.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">The number of daily transactions on the <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Solana?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Solana</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%24SOL&amp;src=ctag&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">$SOL</a> network nears 67 million! <a href="https://t.co/1DIZWjA99S">pic.twitter.com/1DIZWjA99S</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Ali (@ali_charts) <a href="https://twitter.com/ali_charts/status/1869512213859328288?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 18, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Looking at market structure, the falling wedge pattern identified by analysts suggests that Solana is approaching a decision point. This technical formation, characterized by converging trendlines with a downward slope, traditionally resolves with an upward breakout. However, confirmation through increased volume and price action above resistance levels remains necessary.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Institutional interest in Solana continues to evolve, with various investment products tracking the asset&#8217;s performance. The presence of institutional capital provides additional market depth and potentially reduces extreme price volatility. This institutional participation represents a maturing market structure for the asset.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The network&#8217;s transaction metrics reveal consistent usage patterns across different times of day, indicating a globally distributed user base. This geographical diversity in network activity contributes to the platform&#8217;s resilience and suggests sustained adoption across multiple time zones.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Order book analysis shows accumulation patterns at current price levels, with buyers absorbing selling pressure without substantial price degradation. This price action behavior often precedes periods of reduced supply in the market, potentially setting the stage for price appreciation when buying pressure increases.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The latest data shows Solana processing 66.8 million daily transactions as of the most recent network metrics update, with the price holding steady at $210.30 across major exchanges.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blockonomi.com/solana-sol-price-solana-sol-holds-210-support-as-network-activity-hits-new-heights/">Solana (SOL) Price: Solana (SOL) Holds $210 Support as Network Activity Hits New Heights</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blockonomi.com">Blockonomi</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">108706</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>XRP Price: Technical Indicators Show Strong Momentum as Price Holds Above $2.30</title>
		<link>https://blockonomi.com/xrp-price-technical-indicators-show-strong-momentum-as-price-holds-above-2-30/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oliver Dale]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 09:20:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Analysis]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blockonomi.com/?p=108699</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>TLDR XRP has experienced a 17% drop but shows recovery signs, currently trading at $2.31 with a 3.18% daily gain Key bullish factors include Trump&#8217;s potential 2025 inauguration, Gary Gensler&#8217;s expected SEC departure, and possible XRP ETF approval Technical analysis from certified analyst Tony Severino indicates strong bullish signals, including favorable Bollinger Band positioning Market [...]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blockonomi.com/xrp-price-technical-indicators-show-strong-momentum-as-price-holds-above-2-30/">XRP Price: Technical Indicators Show Strong Momentum as Price Holds Above $2.30</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blockonomi.com">Blockonomi</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>TLDR</h2>
<ul>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">XRP has experienced a 17% drop but shows recovery signs, currently trading at $2.31 with a 3.18% daily gain</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Key bullish factors include Trump&#8217;s potential 2025 inauguration, Gary Gensler&#8217;s expected SEC departure, and possible XRP ETF approval</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Technical analysis from certified analyst Tony Severino indicates strong bullish signals, including favorable Bollinger Band positioning</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Market experts predict support levels at $2.17-$2.18, with targets of $2.62 and $3.28 ahead</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">The RLUSD stablecoin launch is expected to drive significant liquidity through the XRP Ledger</li>
</ul>
<hr />
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The XRP token has shown resilience in recent trading, maintaining its position above $2.30 despite a 17% pullback over the past two days. <a href="https://coingape.com/xrp-price-dips-to-2-2-heres-the-key-support-level-to-watch/">Current trading data shows the token has rebounded with a 3.18% gain</a>, aligning with broader market movements and Bitcoin&#8217;s price action.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Market data indicates XRP&#8217;s trading volume remains robust at $21 billion, though this represents a 7% decrease from previous levels. The price action has established a notable support zone between $2.17 and $2.18, which traders are watching closely as a key technical level.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Technical analyst Tony Severino has identified several bullish indicators in XRP&#8217;s three-month chart pattern. The most notable is the position of the price relative to the Bollinger Bands, with the three-month candlestick trading above the Bollinger Band basis for the first time since April 2019.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The Relative Strength Index (RSI) on the three-month timeframe has crossed above its moving average and is approaching the 50 level, which traditionally signals increasing buying pressure. This technical development has caught the attention of traders who view it as a potential precursor to further upward movement.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">I&#39;m potentially not bullish enough on XRP </p>
<p>The XRPBTC quarterly chart looks to be exceptionally strong</p>
<p>From top to bottom: </p>
<p>3M candlestick is above the Bollinger Band basis for the first time since April 2019. Price touched the upper Bollinger Band. A quarterly close above the <a href="https://t.co/2nhaaMqx2R">pic.twitter.com/2nhaaMqx2R</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Tony &quot;The Bull&quot; Severino, CMT (@tonythebullBTC) <a href="https://twitter.com/tonythebullBTC/status/1869440829120479481?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 18, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Market expert EGRAG Crypto has outlined key price targets, identifying $2.62 as the next resistance level, followed by a potential move toward $3.28. These projections are supported by multiple technical factors, including volume patterns and price action structure.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The introduction of RLUSD, Ripple&#8217;s new stablecoin, represents a major development for the<a href="https://moneycheck.com/best-xrp-casinos/"> XRP</a> ecosystem. Market analysts, including The BitBoy, suggest this addition could drive substantial liquidity through the XRP Ledger, potentially supporting price appreciation.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Futures market data from CoinGlass shows an 11% decline in Open Interest, reflecting some reduction in leveraged positions. This cooling of speculative activity might provide a more stable foundation for future price movement.</p>
<figure id="attachment_108700" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-108700" style="width: 847px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-108700" src="https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-09-17-46-XRP-Price-XRP-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko.png" alt="XRP Price on CoinGecko" width="847" height="630" srcset="https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-09-17-46-XRP-Price-XRP-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko.png 847w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-09-17-46-XRP-Price-XRP-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-300x223.png 300w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-09-17-46-XRP-Price-XRP-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-768x571.png 768w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-09-17-46-XRP-Price-XRP-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-50x37.png 50w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-09-17-46-XRP-Price-XRP-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-150x112.png 150w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-09-17-46-XRP-Price-XRP-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-450x335.png 450w" sizes="(max-width: 847px) 100vw, 847px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-108700" class="wp-caption-text">XRP Price on <a href="https://www.coingecko.com/en/coins/xrp">CoinGecko</a></figcaption></figure>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Several external factors could influence XRP&#8217;s price trajectory in the coming months. The potential change in SEC leadership, with Gary Gensler&#8217;s expected departure, has created optimism among market participants who anticipate a more favorable regulatory environment.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The possibility of an XRP ETF approval has generated additional market interest. Bloomberg analysts have suggested that XRP could follow Bitcoin&#8217;s path in receiving ETF approval, which could open the door to increased institutional investment.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Trading patterns show consistent buying pressure at support levels, with $2.17 serving as a strong floor during recent pullbacks. Market technician Dark Defender expects price action to remain within a defined range before attempting another push higher.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Ali Martinez&#8217;s analysis highlights potential market volatility ahead, noting that $20.5 million in short positions face liquidation if XRP reaches $2.62. This technical setup could fuel rapid price movement if certain levels are breached.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Volume analysis shows healthy market participation, with trading activity concentrated around key support and resistance levels. This pattern typically indicates active price discovery and genuine market interest rather than speculative excess.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The token&#8217;s price action has maintained a series of higher lows, suggesting underlying buying pressure remains intact despite recent market volatility. This technical pattern often precedes continued upward movement in traditional market analysis.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Technical indicators such as the Fisher Transform are showing bullish divergence on longer timeframes, supporting the case for sustained price appreciation. This indicator&#8217;s movement often precedes major trend changes in crypto markets.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The three-month Logarithmic MACD displays weakening bearish momentum, with early signs of a potential bullish crossover. This technical development has historically preceded extended upward moves in XRP&#8217;s price action.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blockonomi.com/xrp-price-technical-indicators-show-strong-momentum-as-price-holds-above-2-30/">XRP Price: Technical Indicators Show Strong Momentum as Price Holds Above $2.30</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blockonomi.com">Blockonomi</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">108699</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bitcoin (BTC) Price: Retreats to $97K Following Federal Reserve&#8217;s Hawkish Stance</title>
		<link>https://blockonomi.com/bitcoin-btc-price-bitcoin-btc-retreats-to-97k-following-federal-reserves-hawkish-stance/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oliver Dale]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 09:16:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blockonomi.com/?p=108691</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>TLDR Bitcoin price dropped below $98,000 following the Federal Reserve&#8217;s more hawkish than expected policy outlook Fed projects fewer interest rate cuts in 2025 than previously indicated Bitcoin fell from near record levels to $97,000, with a brief recovery above $102,000 Other cryptocurrencies including Ethereum saw declines of 5% or more Market participants are recalibrating [...]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blockonomi.com/bitcoin-btc-price-bitcoin-btc-retreats-to-97k-following-federal-reserves-hawkish-stance/">Bitcoin (BTC) Price: Retreats to $97K Following Federal Reserve&#8217;s Hawkish Stance</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blockonomi.com">Blockonomi</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>TLDR</h2>
<ul>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Bitcoin price dropped below $98,000 following the Federal Reserve&#8217;s more hawkish than expected policy outlook</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Fed projects fewer interest rate cuts in 2025 than previously indicated</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Bitcoin fell from near record levels to $97,000, with a brief recovery above $102,000</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Other cryptocurrencies including Ethereum saw declines of 5% or more</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Market participants are recalibrating expectations based on Fed&#8217;s stance on maintaining tighter monetary conditions</li>
</ul>
<hr />
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words"><a href="https://bravenewcoin.com/insights/bitcoin-drops-to-97000-following-feds-hawkish-stance">Bitcoin&#8217;s price experienced a sharp decline to $97,000 on Thursday as markets processed the Federal Reserve&#8217;s latest policy announcement.</a> The move came after the central bank delivered its anticipated quarter-point rate reduction but surprised investors with a more conservative outlook for future cuts.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The cryptocurrency market had been riding high in recent weeks, with Bitcoin approaching record levels. However, the Federal Reserve&#8217;s updated projections for 2025 showed fewer planned rate reductions than previously indicated, causing a broad market adjustment.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Trading activity intensified immediately following the Fed&#8217;s announcement. Bitcoin&#8217;s price quickly moved below the $100,000 mark, though it managed to recover briefly above $102,000 before settling around $97,000 during afternoon trading sessions.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The Federal Reserve&#8217;s quarter-point reduction to its benchmark interest rate had been widely expected by market participants. However, the accompanying policy statement and economic projections painted a picture of a central bank determined to maintain a measured approach to monetary policy.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Fed Chair Jerome Powell&#8217;s comments during the post-meeting press conference reinforced this cautious stance. Powell emphasized the importance of maintaining control over inflation while acknowledging the progress made in recent months toward the Fed&#8217;s long-term goals.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The impact of the Fed&#8217;s announcement extended beyond Bitcoin.<a href="https://moneycheck.com/best-ethereum-casinos/"> Ethereum</a>, which holds the second-largest market capitalization in the cryptocurrency space, recorded a decline exceeding 5%. This movement highlighted the broader market&#8217;s sensitivity to monetary policy decisions.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Other cryptocurrencies experienced even steeper declines. Several major altcoins saw double-digit percentage drops as traders adjusted their positions. The so-called &#8220;meme&#8221; tokens, typically more volatile than established cryptocurrencies, faced particularly sharp selloffs.</p>
<figure id="attachment_108693" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-108693" style="width: 847px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-108693" src="https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-09-08-18-Bitcoin-Price-BTC-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko.png" alt="Bitcoin Price on CoinGecko" width="847" height="627" srcset="https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-09-08-18-Bitcoin-Price-BTC-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko.png 847w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-09-08-18-Bitcoin-Price-BTC-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-300x222.png 300w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-09-08-18-Bitcoin-Price-BTC-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-768x569.png 768w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-09-08-18-Bitcoin-Price-BTC-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-50x37.png 50w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-09-08-18-Bitcoin-Price-BTC-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-150x111.png 150w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-09-08-18-Bitcoin-Price-BTC-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-450x333.png 450w" sizes="(max-width: 847px) 100vw, 847px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-108693" class="wp-caption-text">Bitcoin Price on <a href="https://www.coingecko.com/en/coins/bitcoin">CoinGecko</a></figcaption></figure>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Market analysts pointed to the relationship between interest rate expectations and cryptocurrency valuations. Higher interest rates traditionally make speculative assets less attractive to investors, as the opportunity cost of holding non-yielding assets increases.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Trading volumes across major cryptocurrency exchanges surged during the price movement. This increased activity reflected the market&#8217;s rush to reposition portfolios in light of the Fed&#8217;s updated policy path.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Technical analysts noted several key price levels that came into focus during the decline. The $100,000 mark served as a psychological barrier, while the $97,000 level emerged as a point of price stability during the afternoon trading session.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The cryptocurrency market&#8217;s reaction appeared more pronounced than that of traditional financial markets, though stocks and other risk assets also showed sensitivity to the Fed&#8217;s announcement. This heightened reaction in crypto markets underscored the sector&#8217;s continued correlation with broader monetary policy shifts.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Derivatives markets also reflected the changing sentiment.<a href="https://moneycheck.com/best-bitcoin-casinos/"> Bitcoin</a> futures contracts saw increased trading activity, while options markets registered growing demand for downside protection.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Historical data suggests that Bitcoin has often displayed volatility around Federal Reserve policy announcements. However, the scale of this move caught some market participants off guard, given the recent strength in cryptocurrency prices.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Market makers reported that liquidations of leveraged positions contributed to the price movement. As Bitcoin&#8217;s price declined, automated trading systems triggered the closure of long positions, adding to the downward pressure.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The price movement occurred against a backdrop of strong institutional interest in Bitcoin. Recent months had seen increased adoption by traditional financial institutions, though this trend appeared temporarily overshadowed by the immediate market reaction to the Fed&#8217;s stance.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blockonomi.com/bitcoin-btc-price-bitcoin-btc-retreats-to-97k-following-federal-reserves-hawkish-stance/">Bitcoin (BTC) Price: Retreats to $97K Following Federal Reserve&#8217;s Hawkish Stance</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blockonomi.com">Blockonomi</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">108691</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hawk Tuah Sued After Memecoin Pre-Sale Raises $2.8M Before 95% Value Drop</title>
		<link>https://blockonomi.com/hawk-tuah-memecoin-pre-sale-raises-2-8m-before-95-value-drop/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oliver Dale]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 09:05:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Memes]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blockonomi.com/?p=108688</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>TLDR Hailey Welch&#8217;s Hawk Tuah (HAWK) memecoin crashed 95% after launch, wiping out millions in investor funds, leading to her disappearance from public view Investors filed a lawsuit against Tuah The Moon Foundation, OverHere Ltd, Clinton So, and Alex Larson Schultz for alleged securities law violations The pre-sale raised $2.8 million with token valued at [...]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blockonomi.com/hawk-tuah-memecoin-pre-sale-raises-2-8m-before-95-value-drop/">Hawk Tuah Sued After Memecoin Pre-Sale Raises $2.8M Before 95% Value Drop</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blockonomi.com">Blockonomi</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>TLDR</h2>
<ul>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Hailey Welch&#8217;s Hawk Tuah (HAWK) memecoin crashed 95% after launch, wiping out millions in investor funds, leading to her disappearance from public view</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Investors filed a lawsuit against Tuah The Moon Foundation, OverHere Ltd, Clinton So, and Alex Larson Schultz for alleged securities law violations</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">The pre-sale raised $2.8 million with token valued at $16.69 million, before skyrocketing to $491 million market cap and crashing below $100 million</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">On-chain analysis revealed 96% of token supply was concentrated in a few related wallets at launch</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Despite attempts to structure as an offshore entity, the project allegedly targeted US investors, potentially violating securities laws</li>
</ul>
<hr />
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The cryptocurrency community faces another controversy as the <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/news/memecoin-mayhem-hawk-tuah-girl-hailey-welch-faces-lawsuit-after-95-crash/">Hawk Tuah memecoin, promoted by internet personality Hailey Welch, crashed 95% in value,</a> leading to legal action and the creator&#8217;s disappearance from public view.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Welch, known for her &#8220;Talk Tuah&#8221; podcast and &#8220;Hawk Tuah Girl&#8221; persona, last communicated with her audience through a simple message about &#8220;going to sleep.&#8221; This message preceded a massive price collapse that erased hundreds of millions in market value.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The token&#8217;s journey began with a pre-sale that raised $2.8 million, valuing the project at $16.69 million. On December 4, 2024, HAWK launched with explosive momentum, reaching a market capitalization of $491 million within hours. However, the celebration was short-lived as the value plummeted below $100 million shortly after.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words"><a href="https://news.bloomberglaw.com/securities-law/hawk-tuah-memecoin-investors-sue-promoters-over-us-registration?campaign=75902A8A-BE22-11EF-BDB6-F61EE868CE0C">Investors have now filed a lawsuit in the US District Court for the Eastern District of New York.</a> The legal action targets multiple entities: Tuah The Moon Foundation, OverHere Ltd, its founder Clinton So, and influencer Alex Larson Schultz. While Welch is not named as a defendant, her role in promoting the token through social media and her podcast features prominently in the complaint.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The lawsuit alleges losses exceeding $151,000 and claims the token constituted an unregistered security. According to court documents, the defendants attempted to avoid US securities laws by structuring the Tuah The Moon Foundation as an offshore entity. However, the complaint argues they made little effort to restrict token sales to US investors.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">On-chain investigation platform Bubblemaps revealed concerning details about the token&#8217;s distribution. At launch, 96% of HAWK&#8217;s supply was concentrated in a small group of related wallets, raising questions about the project&#8217;s decentralization claims.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr"><a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%24HAWK&amp;src=ctag&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">$HAWK</a> didnt disappoint</p>
<p>96% of the supply in one cluster</p>
<p>nice <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/15.0.3/72x72/1f921.png" alt="" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <a href="https://t.co/AP645QzkfI">https://t.co/AP645QzkfI</a> <a href="https://t.co/ERHTG7v5oa">pic.twitter.com/ERHTG7v5oa</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Bubblemaps (@bubblemaps) <a href="https://twitter.com/bubblemaps/status/1864439521523196046?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 4, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The token&#8217;s economics, dubbed &#8220;Hawkanomics,&#8221; showed that only 2% of the total supply was allocated for public distribution. A larger portion, 17%, was designated as a &#8220;strategic allocation&#8221; that became fully unlocked at launch. These tokens allegedly moved to insider wallets.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Cryptocurrency investigator Coffeezilla raised additional concerns during an X Space discussion. He questioned the team about over $1 million in fees generated from the token and suggested the rapid price decline stemmed from insider trading rather than market dynamics alone.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">This incident adds to a pattern of celebrity-linked memecoin failures in 2024. Similar tokens associated with Andrew Tate, Jason Derulo, and Caitlyn Jenner resulted in substantial losses for holders, each showing similar patterns of concentrated token ownership.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The lawsuit emphasizes how the project leveraged Welch&#8217;s internet fame to market HAWK as an investment opportunity. Many affected investors were fans of Welch&#8217;s content who were new to cryptocurrency trading.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">In response to mounting criticism, Welch has withdrawn from public view, stopping her social media activities and podcast production. The timing of her departure, coinciding with the token&#8217;s collapse, has intensified scrutiny of the project.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Court documents indicate the defendants promoted HAWK through pre-sale campaigns and discounted token offerings. The marketing efforts portrayed token ownership as equivalent to holding shares in the project.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The price collapse occurred within minutes of the token&#8217;s launch, with an 88% drop as major holders quickly sold their positions. This rapid decline triggered immediate concerns about potential market manipulation.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The lawsuit highlights how the project specifically targeted the American market despite claims of being an offshore entity. This detail could prove crucial as US securities laws typically apply when American investors are involved.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blockonomi.com/hawk-tuah-memecoin-pre-sale-raises-2-8m-before-95-value-drop/">Hawk Tuah Sued After Memecoin Pre-Sale Raises $2.8M Before 95% Value Drop</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blockonomi.com">Blockonomi</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">108688</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bitcoin&#8217;s Fall Below $100k Sparks Renewed &#8216;Buy the Dip&#8217; Discussions: Santiment</title>
		<link>https://blockonomi.com/bitcoins-fall-below-100k-sparks-renewed-buy-the-dip-discussions-santiment/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nicholas Say]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 09:04:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blockonomi.com/?p=108681</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Even as Bitcoin sinks below $100,000, the cryptocurrency market is buzzing with buy the dip sentiment. Data from blockchain analysis platform Santiment reveals that online discussions about buying the dip are at an eight-month high, which indicates that many investors see the recent sell-off as a buying opportunity. The Crypto Fear and Greed Index is [...]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blockonomi.com/bitcoins-fall-below-100k-sparks-renewed-buy-the-dip-discussions-santiment/">Bitcoin&#8217;s Fall Below $100k Sparks Renewed &#8216;Buy the Dip&#8217; Discussions: Santiment</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blockonomi.com">Blockonomi</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Even as Bitcoin sinks below $100,000, the cryptocurrency market is <a href="https://cointelegraph.com/news/crypto-social-media-mentions-buy-the-dip-surges-bitcoin-100k-price-level-santiment">buzzing with buy the dip</a> sentiment. Data from blockchain analysis platform Santiment reveals that online discussions about buying the dip are at an eight-month high, which indicates that many investors see the recent sell-off as a buying opportunity.</p>
<p>The Crypto Fear and Greed Index is still in the greed zone. With a lot of people looking for big gains, there could be more pain ahead.</p>
<blockquote><p><em>The ratio of crypto discussions that are about buying crypto&#8217;s dip has reached its highest level in over 8 months. The last time we saw the crowd nearly this enthusiastic about dip buying was the major crash on August 4th. Since that time, Bitcoin&#8217;s market cap is +81% higher,</em> Santiment noted in a statement.</p></blockquote>
<p>Data shows a clear link between major Bitcoin price drops and increased buying the dip sentiment on social media. The crypto Trump rally was great, but it looks like it is over.</p>
<h2>Lower Prices to Come?</h2>
<p>As reported, the social dominance score which tracks mentions of buying the dip on social channels climbed to 0.061, the highest level since April 12. That day, Bitcoin fell below $70,000 and extended its correction to around $63,000 the following day.</p>
<p>Data also shows a similar spike in buying the dip talks on August 4, when Bitcoin sank under $60,000 and slid further to around $53,000.</p>
<p>Bitcoin began a sharp price correction on Thursday, declining from $102,000 to below $96,000. It is currently trading at $97,700, reflecting a 3.6% decrease over the past 24 hours. Despite this recent downturn, the flagship cryptocurrency still shows a 128% gain year-to-date, per CoinGecko.</p>
<p>Altcoins are faring even worse. Many cryptocurrencies posted two-digit losses in a day. Over the past 24 hours, Dogecoin (DOGE) shed 12%, Ether fell nearly 8% to $3,400, and Solana plummeted 8.6% to $193. Ripple (XRP), meanwhile, saw a decline of 3%.</p>
<h2>Rate Worries</h2>
<p>Market turbulence intensified following the Federal Reserve&#8217;s Wednesday monetary policy meeting, where the central bank announced a 0.25 percentage point cut in interest rates, lowering its benchmark rate to a range of 4.25% to 4.5%.</p>
<p>Despite the widely expected rate cut, market participants focused more on the banks approach to monetary policy in 2025. The Fed, however, delivered surprisingly hawkish messages for the coming year.</p>
<p>The Fed projects only two quarter-point rate cuts in 2025, a change from previous projections, where four cuts were anticipated. The Fed&#8217;s cautious outlook is influenced by persistent inflation and a robust economy, leading to a more gradual approach to monetary easing.</p>
<p>Fed Chair Jerome Powell stated that the Fed is committed to achieving its target inflation at 2%. The November inflation rate in the US rose to 2.7%, up from 2.6% in October, which matched forecasts but remains above the banks goal.</p>
<p>Inflation is still elevated and above the banks goal despite economic activity continuing to expand, which prompts the Fed to carefully assess incoming economic data and risks before making further adjustments.</p>
<p>Not only that, the incoming administration of President-elect Donald Trump, sparks widespread concerns about accelerating inflation, though Trumps proposed economic policies are kept unknown as of now.</p>
<p>Global markets reacted negatively to the Fed&#8217;s communication. Stock markets, in the meantime, crashed harder. Major indices suffered losses, with the S&amp;P 500 falling approximately 3%, the Dow Jones Industrial Average dropping around 100 points, and the Nasdaq Composite declining by about 3.6%.</p>
<p>Over $1 trillion was wiped out from the stock markets following the Feds policy meeting. Big falls may impact the FED, but inflation is an issue no matter what.</p>
<p>Bitcoin&#8217;s price quickly declined below $100,000, dropping to around $98,760 at one point during Powell&#8217;s remarks, before recovering slightly later. Yet the Crypto Fear and Greed Index, which gauges the overall sentiment of the cryptocurrency market, still sticks in the greed zone post-FOMC meeting.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blockonomi.com/bitcoins-fall-below-100k-sparks-renewed-buy-the-dip-discussions-santiment/">Bitcoin&#8217;s Fall Below $100k Sparks Renewed &#8216;Buy the Dip&#8217; Discussions: Santiment</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blockonomi.com">Blockonomi</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">108681</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ethereum (ETH) Price: Market Weighs Impact of 7.8M Token Binance Withdrawal</title>
		<link>https://blockonomi.com/ethereum-eth-price-market-weighs-impact-of-7-8m-token-binance-withdrawal/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oliver Dale]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 11:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ethereum]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blockonomi.com/?p=108638</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>TLDR 20.8 million ETH withdrawn from centralized exchanges in past two months, with Binance accounting for 7.8 million ETH (33-39% of total outflows) ETH currently trading at $3,858, down 2.4% in 24 hours and 21.1% below all-time high of $4,878 Deutsche Bank reportedly developing Layer-2 blockchain on Ethereum using ZKsync technology ETH has underperformed compared [...]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blockonomi.com/ethereum-eth-price-market-weighs-impact-of-7-8m-token-binance-withdrawal/">Ethereum (ETH) Price: Market Weighs Impact of 7.8M Token Binance Withdrawal</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blockonomi.com">Blockonomi</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>TLDR</h2>
<ul>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">20.8 million ETH withdrawn from centralized exchanges in past two months, with Binance accounting for 7.8 million ETH (33-39% of total outflows)</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">ETH currently trading at $3,858, down 2.4% in 24 hours and 21.1% below all-time high of $4,878</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Deutsche Bank reportedly developing Layer-2 blockchain on Ethereum using ZKsync technology</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">ETH has underperformed compared to Bitcoin, showing only 2.3% gain vs Bitcoin&#8217;s 5% gain in past week</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Technical analysts suggest potential price correction to $3,400 based on bearish chart patterns</li>
</ul>
<hr />
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">A substantial shift in <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/news/ethereum/7-8m-ethereum-leaves-binance-in-two-months-what-does-this-mean-for-eth/">Ethereum market dynamics has emerged over the past two months, with data showing massive withdrawals from centralized exchanges</a>, particularly Binance. According to CryptoQuant, approximately 20.8 million ETH have been moved off exchanges during this period, echoing patterns seen during the 2021 bull market.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Binance, the world&#8217;s largest cryptocurrency exchange, has been at the center of this movement. The platform has recorded withdrawals of over 7.8 million ETH, representing between 33% and 39% of the total outflows from all centralized exchanges combined.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The price of Ethereum currently stands at $3,858, showing a 2.4% decrease over the past 24 hours. This places the second-largest cryptocurrency by market capitalization about 21.1% below its all-time high of $4,878, which was achieved in 2021.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words"><a href="https://cryptoquant.com/insights/quicktake/67629bb63ed5b60349210bd9-Binance-Dominates-Ethereum-Outflows-78-Million-ETH-in-Just-Two-Months">CryptoQuant analyst</a> Crazzyblockk suggests these withdrawals could indicate investors are accumulating ETH for long-term holding or staking purposes. The scale of these movements from Binance is particularly noteworthy given the exchange&#8217;s global reach, with a user base of 250 million and reported deposits of $21.6 billion this year.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The timing of these withdrawals coincides with news that Deutsche Bank, Germany&#8217;s largest lender, is reportedly developing its own layer-2 blockchain solution on Ethereum using ZKsync technology. This development represents another major financial institution stepping into the Ethereum ecosystem.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Despite these seemingly positive developments, Ethereum&#8217;s price performance has lagged behind Bitcoin during the recent crypto market rally. While Bitcoin has consistently reached new all-time highs in recent months, Ethereum has struggled to break through the $4,000 resistance level.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">JUST IN: Deutsche Bank building its own Layer-2 on Ethereum &#8211; Bloomberg <a href="https://t.co/5O5K3R1fRg">pic.twitter.com/5O5K3R1fRg</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Radar<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/15.0.3/72x72/1f6a8.png" alt="" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> (@RadarHits) <a href="https://twitter.com/RadarHits/status/1869398222789308483?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 18, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The past week&#8217;s trading data highlights this divergence, with ETH showing a modest 2.3% increase compared to Bitcoin&#8217;s more robust 5% gain over the same period. This underperformance comes even as institutional interest in Ethereum appears to be growing.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Technical analysts have identified potential bearish signals in <a href="https://moneycheck.com/best-ethereum-casinos/">Ethereum</a>&#8216;s price charts. Some market observers point to the formation of a bearish double top pattern, accompanied by bearish divergence in the Relative Strength Index (RSI) and a Moving Average Convergence Divergence (MACD) crossover confirming the downward trend.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">These technical indicators suggest a possible price correction to the $3,400 level, with major support levels established at $3,200 and $3,000. However, trading volumes remain relatively stable, indicating no immediate signs of panic selling.</p>
<figure id="attachment_108644" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-108644" style="width: 847px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-108644" src="https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-19-at-11-10-41-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko.png" alt="Ethereum Price on CoinGecko" width="847" height="630" srcset="https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-19-at-11-10-41-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko.png 847w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-19-at-11-10-41-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-300x223.png 300w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-19-at-11-10-41-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-768x571.png 768w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-19-at-11-10-41-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-50x37.png 50w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-19-at-11-10-41-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-150x112.png 150w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-19-at-11-10-41-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-450x335.png 450w" sizes="(max-width: 847px) 100vw, 847px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-108644" class="wp-caption-text">Ethereum Price on <a href="https://www.coingecko.com/en/coins/ethereum">CoinGecko</a></figcaption></figure>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The exchange outflows have reduced the available supply of ETH on trading platforms, which typically creates upward pressure on prices if demand remains steady or increases. However, this traditional market dynamic hasn&#8217;t yet manifested in higher prices.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Market data shows that the withdrawal pattern has been consistent rather than sudden, suggesting a methodical approach by ETH holders rather than reactive movement to market events. The steady nature of these withdrawals implies long-term strategic positioning by investors.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Binance&#8217;s role in these withdrawals has drawn particular attention from market analysts. The exchange&#8217;s influence on the cryptocurrency market remains substantial, as evidenced by its ability to process such large-scale movements of ETH without causing major market disruptions.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The current price action occurs against a backdrop of broader cryptocurrency market maturation, with traditional financial institutions increasingly engaging with blockchain technology. Deutsche Bank&#8217;s reported layer-2 development represents just one example of this trend.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Daily trading volumes for ETH have remained within normal ranges despite the large exchange outflows, suggesting that market liquidity hasn&#8217;t been substantially impacted by the withdrawals. This stability in trading activity indicates that the market has absorbed the changes in exchange balances without major disruption.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Recent price data shows ETH trading in a consolidation pattern between $3,800 and $4,000, with neither bulls nor bears gaining clear control of the market momentum. The most recent trading session closed at $3,858, with volume indicators showing neutral market sentiment.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blockonomi.com/ethereum-eth-price-market-weighs-impact-of-7-8m-token-binance-withdrawal/">Ethereum (ETH) Price: Market Weighs Impact of 7.8M Token Binance Withdrawal</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blockonomi.com">Blockonomi</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">108638</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
