<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Ethereum News &amp; Updates: Latest Live Info About ETH from Blockonomi</title>
	<atom:link href="https://blockonomi.com/ethereum/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://blockonomi.com/ethereum/</link>
	<description>Cryptocurrency News &#38; Your Guide to the Blockchain Economy</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 10:23:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.7.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/fav-50x50.png</url>
	<title>Ethereum News &amp; Updates: Latest Live Info About ETH from Blockonomi</title>
	<link>https://blockonomi.com/ethereum/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">134176212</site>	<item>
		<title>Ethereum (ETH) Price Update: Price Action Suggests Bearish Momentum Below $3,650</title>
		<link>https://blockonomi.com/ethereum-eth-price-update-price-action-suggests-bearish-momentum-below-3650/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oliver Dale]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 10:23:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ethereum]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blockonomi.com/?p=108753</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>TLDR Ethereum has experienced a sharp decline, dropping below $3,680 and currently trading under $3,550 A key bearish trend line has formed with resistance at $3,650 on the hourly chart The cryptocurrency reached a low of $3,324, with current major support at $3,320 Technical indicators, including MACD and RSI, suggest continued bearish momentum Recovery would [...]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blockonomi.com/ethereum-eth-price-update-price-action-suggests-bearish-momentum-below-3650/">Ethereum (ETH) Price Update: Price Action Suggests Bearish Momentum Below $3,650</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blockonomi.com">Blockonomi</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>TLDR</h2>
<ul>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Ethereum has experienced a sharp decline, dropping below $3,680 and currently trading under $3,550</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">A key bearish trend line has formed with resistance at $3,650 on the hourly chart</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">The cryptocurrency reached a low of $3,324, with current major support at $3,320</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Technical indicators, including MACD and RSI, suggest continued bearish momentum</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Recovery would require breaking through multiple resistance levels, with $3,715 being a crucial point</li>
</ul>
<hr />
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Ethereum&#8217;s price trajectory has taken a downward turn, with the leading altcoin dropping below several key support levels in recent hours. <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/analysis/eth/ethereum-price-plunge-3320/">The cryptocurrency has fallen more than 7% and is currently trading below the $3,550 mark, showing continued bearish pressure in the short term.</a></p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The decline began as Ethereum struggled to maintain momentum above the $3,680 level, leading to a cascade of technical support breaks. The price action mirrors the broader market movement, with Bitcoin also experiencing similar downward pressure during the same period.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Trading data from Kraken shows that Ethereum&#8217;s price movement has broken below the 100-hourly Simple Moving Average, a technical indicator often used to determine market trends. This break suggests that bears have gained control of the immediate price action.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The depth of the current decline became apparent as Ethereum&#8217;s price continued to slide, eventually reaching a local low of $3,324. This price point represents a notable departure from recent trading ranges and has established a new support level that traders are watching closely.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Technical analysis of the hourly chart reveals the formation of a bearish trend line with resistance positioned at $3,650. This pattern suggests that any attempted recovery will face strong selling pressure at these higher levels.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Current market data indicates that <a href="https://moneycheck.com/best-ethereum-casinos/">Ethereum</a> is consolidating around the $3,510 level, which coincides with the 23.6% Fibonacci retracement level. This technical measure takes into account the recent price swing from $4,105 to the low of $3,324.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">For traders looking at potential recovery scenarios, the first major hurdle appears at the $3,650 mark. This level is reinforced by the previously mentioned bearish trend line, making it a crucial point for any potential upward movement.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">A more substantial resistance level has formed near $3,715, which represents the 50% Fibonacci retracement level of the recent downward movement. This price point could prove to be a key battleground between bulls and bears in the coming trading sessions.</p>
<figure id="attachment_108754" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-108754" style="width: 847px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-108754" src="https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-10-20-45-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko.png" alt="Ethereum Price on CoinGecko" width="847" height="625" srcset="https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-10-20-45-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko.png 847w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-10-20-45-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-300x221.png 300w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-10-20-45-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-768x567.png 768w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-10-20-45-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-50x37.png 50w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-10-20-45-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-150x111.png 150w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-10-20-45-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-450x332.png 450w" sizes="(max-width: 847px) 100vw, 847px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-108754" class="wp-caption-text">Ethereum Price on <a href="https://www.coingecko.com/en/coins/ethereum">CoinGecko</a></figcaption></figure>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Should buyers manage to push the price above these immediate resistance levels, the next major target would be the $3,800 mark. A successful break above this point could open the path toward the psychologically important $4,000 level.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">However, the current technical setup suggests that downside risks remain prevalent. The immediate support level to watch is near $3,350, with a more substantial support zone established around $3,320.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">If selling pressure continues and Ethereum fails to hold these support levels, the next potential landing zones appear at $3,250 and $3,150. Technical traders are particularly watching the $3,050 level as a crucial support point that could come into play if the current bearish momentum persists.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The hourly MACD (Moving Average Convergence Divergence) indicator is showing increasing momentum in the bearish zone, adding weight to the negative short-term outlook. This technical indicator is often used to measure trend strength and direction.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Similarly, the RSI (Relative Strength Index) for ETH/USD has dropped below the 50 zone, suggesting that bearish pressure currently dominates the market sentiment. The RSI is a momentum indicator that helps traders identify overbought or oversold conditions.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Trading volume data indicates increased selling activity during this price decline, with multiple large transactions recorded as the price broke through various support levels.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The price action has created a series of lower highs and lower lows on the hourly chart, a pattern that typically indicates a continuing downward trend in technical analysis.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Market data shows that order books are currently weighted toward the sell side, with substantial resistance building up near the $3,650 level.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Recent price action has led to the liquidation of multiple long positions, contributing to the downward pressure as forced selling triggers additional price declines.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Hourly chart patterns suggest the formation of a bearish flag, indicating that the current consolidation might be temporary before another potential move lower.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blockonomi.com/ethereum-eth-price-update-price-action-suggests-bearish-momentum-below-3650/">Ethereum (ETH) Price Update: Price Action Suggests Bearish Momentum Below $3,650</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blockonomi.com">Blockonomi</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">108753</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bitwise CIO Projects Ethereum Advancement Through Layer-2 Solutions</title>
		<link>https://blockonomi.com/bitwise-cio-projects-ethereum-advancement-through-layer-2-solutions/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oliver Dale]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 11:19:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ethereum]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blockonomi.com/?p=108646</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>TLDR Bitwise CIO Matt Hougan forecasts Ethereum to surpass Solana in 2025, driven by Layer-2 network improvements Ethereum&#8217;s Layer-2 solutions are transforming its reputation for being slow and expensive AI projects like Clanker are thriving on Ethereum&#8217;s Base network, showing its adaptability VanEck predicts ETH to reach $6,000 and SOL to hit $500 by 2025 [...]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blockonomi.com/bitwise-cio-projects-ethereum-advancement-through-layer-2-solutions/">Bitwise CIO Projects Ethereum Advancement Through Layer-2 Solutions</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blockonomi.com">Blockonomi</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>TLDR</h2>
<ul>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Bitwise CIO Matt Hougan forecasts Ethereum to surpass Solana in 2025, driven by Layer-2 network improvements</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Ethereum&#8217;s Layer-2 solutions are transforming its reputation for being slow and expensive</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">AI projects like Clanker are thriving on Ethereum&#8217;s Base network, showing its adaptability</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">VanEck predicts ETH to reach $6,000 and SOL to hit $500 by 2025</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Solana recently overtook Ethereum in monthly active developers with 83% year-over-year growth</li>
</ul>
<hr />
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The battle between Ethereum and Solana continues to heat up as industry experts make bold predictions for 2025. <a href="https://coingape.com/bitwise-cio-matt-hougan-says-ethereum-to-outpace-solana-in-2025-heres-why/">Matt Hougan, Chief Investment Officer at Bitwise, has shared his outlook on Ethereum&#8217;s future, pointing to Layer-2 networks as the key driver of growth.</a></p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Layer-2 solutions like Base, Optimism, and Arbitrum are changing how people view Ethereum. These networks help solve the platform&#8217;s old problems of high costs and slow transactions. Hougan believes these improvements will help Ethereum compete more effectively with Solana, which has been known for being faster and cheaper to use.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">AI projects are finding a home on Ethereum&#8217;s network, particularly through its Layer-2 solution called Base. Projects like Clanker and Virtuals show that Ethereum can support new types of applications while keeping its strong security features. This development proves that the platform can adapt to new technologies while maintaining trust from big institutions.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">People&#39;s mental model of Ethereum is out of date. The common consensus is Solana is cheap/easy/fun and Ethereum is slow/unwieldy/expensive.  </p>
<p>But look at what&#39;s happening in the AI agent space. Some of the most exciting &quot;fun&quot; projects, like Clanker and Virtuals, are playing out…</p>
<p>&mdash; Matt Hougan (@Matt_Hougan) <a href="https://twitter.com/Matt_Hougan/status/1869483554197086657?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 18, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The growth of Layer-2 networks is making Ethereum more accessible to everyday users. These solutions allow for faster transactions and lower fees, addressing two of the biggest complaints about Ethereum in the past. Developers can now build applications that are both secure and user-friendly.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">VanEck, another major player in the crypto industry, has made some interesting price predictions. They expect Ethereum&#8217;s price to go above $6,000 by 2025, while <a href="https://moneycheck.com/best-solana-casinos/">Solana</a> could reach $500. These predictions are based on continued growth in areas like decentralized finance (DeFi) and non-fungible tokens (NFTs).</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Ethereum&#8217;s Layer-2 networks are becoming increasingly important for the platform&#8217;s success. They work by processing transactions outside the main blockchain, which makes everything faster and cheaper. This approach helps Ethereum handle more users without getting bogged down.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The competition between Ethereum and Solana remains fierce. Solana recently achieved an important milestone by becoming the leading platform for new developers. According to data from Electric Capital, Solana saw an 83% increase in monthly active developers compared to the previous year.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">This growth ended <a href="https://moneycheck.com/best-ethereum-casinos/">Ethereum&#8217;s</a> eight-year streak as the top platform for developer activity. However, Hougan maintains his positive outlook on Ethereum&#8217;s future, particularly due to its Layer-2 developments.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Both platforms are showing strengths in different areas. While Solana attracts new developers with its speed and low costs, Ethereum continues to build trust with institutions and expand its capabilities through Layer-2 networks.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The rise of AI projects on Ethereum&#8217;s network shows how the platform is evolving. Through Base and other Layer-2 solutions, developers can create advanced applications that weren&#8217;t possible before due to cost and speed limitations.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Hougan emphasized that Ethereum&#8217;s ability to maintain institutional trust while becoming easier to use will be crucial for its success in 2025. The platform&#8217;s Layer-2 networks are making this possible by providing the scalability needed for widespread adoption.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The growth in developer activity across both platforms indicates a healthy ecosystem. While Solana leads in attracting new developers, Ethereum continues to expand its technological capabilities through Layer-2 solutions.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">User experience remains a key focus for both networks. Ethereum&#8217;s Layer-2 solutions are making the platform more accessible, while Solana maintains its reputation for speed and efficiency.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Recent developments in AI and blockchain technology are creating new opportunities for both platforms. Projects like Clanker on Ethereum&#8217;s Base network demonstrate how blockchain technology can support advanced applications.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">VanEck&#8217;s price predictions suggest confidence in both platforms&#8217; futures. Their forecast of $6,000 for Ethereum and $500 for Solana indicates potential growth across the blockchain sector.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blockonomi.com/bitwise-cio-projects-ethereum-advancement-through-layer-2-solutions/">Bitwise CIO Projects Ethereum Advancement Through Layer-2 Solutions</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blockonomi.com">Blockonomi</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">108646</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ethereum (ETH) Price: Market Weighs Impact of 7.8M Token Binance Withdrawal</title>
		<link>https://blockonomi.com/ethereum-eth-price-market-weighs-impact-of-7-8m-token-binance-withdrawal/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oliver Dale]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 11:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ethereum]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blockonomi.com/?p=108638</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>TLDR 20.8 million ETH withdrawn from centralized exchanges in past two months, with Binance accounting for 7.8 million ETH (33-39% of total outflows) ETH currently trading at $3,858, down 2.4% in 24 hours and 21.1% below all-time high of $4,878 Deutsche Bank reportedly developing Layer-2 blockchain on Ethereum using ZKsync technology ETH has underperformed compared [...]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blockonomi.com/ethereum-eth-price-market-weighs-impact-of-7-8m-token-binance-withdrawal/">Ethereum (ETH) Price: Market Weighs Impact of 7.8M Token Binance Withdrawal</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blockonomi.com">Blockonomi</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>TLDR</h2>
<ul>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">20.8 million ETH withdrawn from centralized exchanges in past two months, with Binance accounting for 7.8 million ETH (33-39% of total outflows)</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">ETH currently trading at $3,858, down 2.4% in 24 hours and 21.1% below all-time high of $4,878</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Deutsche Bank reportedly developing Layer-2 blockchain on Ethereum using ZKsync technology</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">ETH has underperformed compared to Bitcoin, showing only 2.3% gain vs Bitcoin&#8217;s 5% gain in past week</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Technical analysts suggest potential price correction to $3,400 based on bearish chart patterns</li>
</ul>
<hr />
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">A substantial shift in <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/news/ethereum/7-8m-ethereum-leaves-binance-in-two-months-what-does-this-mean-for-eth/">Ethereum market dynamics has emerged over the past two months, with data showing massive withdrawals from centralized exchanges</a>, particularly Binance. According to CryptoQuant, approximately 20.8 million ETH have been moved off exchanges during this period, echoing patterns seen during the 2021 bull market.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Binance, the world&#8217;s largest cryptocurrency exchange, has been at the center of this movement. The platform has recorded withdrawals of over 7.8 million ETH, representing between 33% and 39% of the total outflows from all centralized exchanges combined.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The price of Ethereum currently stands at $3,858, showing a 2.4% decrease over the past 24 hours. This places the second-largest cryptocurrency by market capitalization about 21.1% below its all-time high of $4,878, which was achieved in 2021.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words"><a href="https://cryptoquant.com/insights/quicktake/67629bb63ed5b60349210bd9-Binance-Dominates-Ethereum-Outflows-78-Million-ETH-in-Just-Two-Months">CryptoQuant analyst</a> Crazzyblockk suggests these withdrawals could indicate investors are accumulating ETH for long-term holding or staking purposes. The scale of these movements from Binance is particularly noteworthy given the exchange&#8217;s global reach, with a user base of 250 million and reported deposits of $21.6 billion this year.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The timing of these withdrawals coincides with news that Deutsche Bank, Germany&#8217;s largest lender, is reportedly developing its own layer-2 blockchain solution on Ethereum using ZKsync technology. This development represents another major financial institution stepping into the Ethereum ecosystem.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Despite these seemingly positive developments, Ethereum&#8217;s price performance has lagged behind Bitcoin during the recent crypto market rally. While Bitcoin has consistently reached new all-time highs in recent months, Ethereum has struggled to break through the $4,000 resistance level.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">JUST IN: Deutsche Bank building its own Layer-2 on Ethereum &#8211; Bloomberg <a href="https://t.co/5O5K3R1fRg">pic.twitter.com/5O5K3R1fRg</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Radar<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/15.0.3/72x72/1f6a8.png" alt="🚨" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> (@RadarHits) <a href="https://twitter.com/RadarHits/status/1869398222789308483?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 18, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The past week&#8217;s trading data highlights this divergence, with ETH showing a modest 2.3% increase compared to Bitcoin&#8217;s more robust 5% gain over the same period. This underperformance comes even as institutional interest in Ethereum appears to be growing.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Technical analysts have identified potential bearish signals in <a href="https://moneycheck.com/best-ethereum-casinos/">Ethereum</a>&#8216;s price charts. Some market observers point to the formation of a bearish double top pattern, accompanied by bearish divergence in the Relative Strength Index (RSI) and a Moving Average Convergence Divergence (MACD) crossover confirming the downward trend.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">These technical indicators suggest a possible price correction to the $3,400 level, with major support levels established at $3,200 and $3,000. However, trading volumes remain relatively stable, indicating no immediate signs of panic selling.</p>
<figure id="attachment_108644" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-108644" style="width: 847px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-108644" src="https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-19-at-11-10-41-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko.png" alt="Ethereum Price on CoinGecko" width="847" height="630" srcset="https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-19-at-11-10-41-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko.png 847w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-19-at-11-10-41-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-300x223.png 300w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-19-at-11-10-41-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-768x571.png 768w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-19-at-11-10-41-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-50x37.png 50w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-19-at-11-10-41-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-150x112.png 150w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-19-at-11-10-41-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-450x335.png 450w" sizes="(max-width: 847px) 100vw, 847px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-108644" class="wp-caption-text">Ethereum Price on <a href="https://www.coingecko.com/en/coins/ethereum">CoinGecko</a></figcaption></figure>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The exchange outflows have reduced the available supply of ETH on trading platforms, which typically creates upward pressure on prices if demand remains steady or increases. However, this traditional market dynamic hasn&#8217;t yet manifested in higher prices.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Market data shows that the withdrawal pattern has been consistent rather than sudden, suggesting a methodical approach by ETH holders rather than reactive movement to market events. The steady nature of these withdrawals implies long-term strategic positioning by investors.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Binance&#8217;s role in these withdrawals has drawn particular attention from market analysts. The exchange&#8217;s influence on the cryptocurrency market remains substantial, as evidenced by its ability to process such large-scale movements of ETH without causing major market disruptions.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The current price action occurs against a backdrop of broader cryptocurrency market maturation, with traditional financial institutions increasingly engaging with blockchain technology. Deutsche Bank&#8217;s reported layer-2 development represents just one example of this trend.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Daily trading volumes for ETH have remained within normal ranges despite the large exchange outflows, suggesting that market liquidity hasn&#8217;t been substantially impacted by the withdrawals. This stability in trading activity indicates that the market has absorbed the changes in exchange balances without major disruption.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Recent price data shows ETH trading in a consolidation pattern between $3,800 and $4,000, with neither bulls nor bears gaining clear control of the market momentum. The most recent trading session closed at $3,858, with volume indicators showing neutral market sentiment.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blockonomi.com/ethereum-eth-price-market-weighs-impact-of-7-8m-token-binance-withdrawal/">Ethereum (ETH) Price: Market Weighs Impact of 7.8M Token Binance Withdrawal</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blockonomi.com">Blockonomi</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">108638</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ethereum (ETH) Price: Tests $4,000 as ETF Products See Record-Breaking Inflows</title>
		<link>https://blockonomi.com/ethereum-eth-price-tests-4000-as-etf-products-see-record-breaking-inflows/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oliver Dale]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 09:23:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ethereum]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blockonomi.com/?p=108478</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>TLDR Ethereum spot ETFs have seen 16 consecutive days of positive inflows, totaling $2.32 billion since November 22 Total net assets held by Ethereum ETFs have reached $14.28 billion, representing 2.93% of ETH&#8217;s circulating supply Grayscale&#8217;s Ethereum Trust leads with $5.87 billion in assets, followed by Blackrock&#8217;s iShares at $4.02 billion Current trading price around [...]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blockonomi.com/ethereum-eth-price-tests-4000-as-etf-products-see-record-breaking-inflows/">Ethereum (ETH) Price: Tests $4,000 as ETF Products See Record-Breaking Inflows</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blockonomi.com">Blockonomi</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>TLDR</h2>
<ul>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Ethereum spot ETFs have seen 16 consecutive days of positive inflows, totaling $2.32 billion since November 22</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Total net assets held by Ethereum ETFs have reached $14.28 billion, representing 2.93% of ETH&#8217;s circulating supply</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Grayscale&#8217;s Ethereum Trust leads with $5.87 billion in assets, followed by Blackrock&#8217;s iShares at $4.02 billion</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Current trading price around $3,947, with resistance at $4,000 level</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Net outflows from exchanges suggest reduced selling pressure and potential bullish momentum</li>
</ul>
<hr />
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Ethereum spot exchange-traded funds continue to attract substantial investor interest, marking an unbroken 16-day streak of positive inflows since November 22.<a href="https://sosovalue.com/assets/etf/us-eth-spot"> Data from SoSoValue</a> shows these ETFs have accumulated $2.32 billion in net inflows during this period.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words"><a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/news/ethereum/ethereum-sees-net-outflows-on-spot-exchanges-is-a-major-price-rally-coming/">The week ending December 13 brought in $854.85 million in new investments</a>, while the previous week saw inflows of $836.69 million. This steady flow of capital has pushed the total net assets held by Ethereum ETFs to $14.28 billion.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Grayscale&#8217;s Ethereum Trust has emerged as the market leader, managing $5.87 billion in assets. Blackrock&#8217;s iShares Ethereum Trust follows with $4.02 billion under management. Together, these ETFs now hold approximately 2.93% of Ethereum&#8217;s total circulating supply.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The price of Ethereum has responded to this institutional interest, trading near the $4,000 mark. This level has proven to be a key resistance point, with four major attempts to break through it in recent history.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Technical analyst Rekt Capital points out that Ethereum has maintained support above $3,100 following a recent breakout. The cryptocurrency has now held above the $4,000 zone as support for two consecutive weeks, potentially setting the stage for further price movement.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr"><a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%24ETH&amp;src=ctag&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">$ETH</a> looks good to break through the local highs and go for $4.5K</p>
<p>Ethereum inflows have been coming in non-stop for the last few weeks!</p>
<p>After seeing <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%24BTC&amp;src=ctag&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">$BTC</a> at $107K&#8230;. I think institutions don&#39;t have much options left to bet on higher upside of crypto industry!</p>
<p>Higher! <a href="https://t.co/56SqHH0NsE">pic.twitter.com/56SqHH0NsE</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Momin (@mominsaqib) <a href="https://twitter.com/mominsaqib/status/1868978195480903968?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 17, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Market watchers note that Ethereum&#8217;s path to new highs faces several technical hurdles. The previous all-time high of $4,878 serves as a reminder that breaking through key resistance levels requires sustained buying pressure.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Some traders are taking a measured approach to current market conditions. Analyst CryptoBullet suggests the possibility of a brief dip to $3,700 before any continued upward movement, highlighting the importance of key support levels.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The flow of <a href="https://moneycheck.com/best-ethereum-casinos/">Ethereum</a> on exchanges provides additional insight into market sentiment. Net outflows from exchanges typically indicate investors moving their holdings to long-term storage, which can reduce selling pressure in the market.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Recent data shows a pattern of withdrawals from exchanges, suggesting holders may be preparing for longer-term positions. This behavior often precedes periods of price appreciation, as fewer tokens are readily available for trading.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">However, market participants are watching several factors that could impact price action. Justin Sun, founder of Tron, recently unstaked $208 million worth of ETH from Lido Finance, introducing potential selling pressure to the market.</p>
<figure id="attachment_108487" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-108487" style="width: 847px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-108487" src="https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-18-at-09-19-54-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko.png" alt="Ethereum Price on CoinGecko" width="847" height="628" srcset="https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-18-at-09-19-54-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko.png 847w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-18-at-09-19-54-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-300x222.png 300w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-18-at-09-19-54-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-768x569.png 768w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-18-at-09-19-54-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-50x37.png 50w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-18-at-09-19-54-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-150x111.png 150w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-18-at-09-19-54-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-450x334.png 450w" sizes="(max-width: 847px) 100vw, 847px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-108487" class="wp-caption-text">Ethereum Price on <a href="https://www.coingecko.com/en/coins/ethereum">CoinGecko</a></figcaption></figure>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The sustained inflow into ETF products marks a shift in how institutional investors approach cryptocurrency exposure. These regulated investment vehicles provide a familiar framework for traditional finance participants to gain exposure to Ethereum.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Breaking down the weekly flows shows consistency in investor appetite. The two-week period from December 1 to December 13 brought in over $1.6 billion in new investments, demonstrating steady institutional demand.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Trade volume across ETF products has remained robust, indicating active participation from both retail and institutional investors. This increased liquidity helps support price discovery and market stability.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Market data reveals that ETF holders are predominantly taking long-term positions rather than engaging in short-term trading. This buy-and-hold behavior aligns with institutional investment strategies typically seen in traditional markets.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The relationship between ETF inflows and market prices continues to evolve as the products mature. Daily trading patterns show correlation between periods of high inflow and positive price movement.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blockonomi.com/ethereum-eth-price-tests-4000-as-etf-products-see-record-breaking-inflows/">Ethereum (ETH) Price: Tests $4,000 as ETF Products See Record-Breaking Inflows</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blockonomi.com">Blockonomi</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">108478</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ethereum (ETH) Price: Ethereum Shows Strong Support Above $3,900 Level</title>
		<link>https://blockonomi.com/ethereum-eth-price-ethereum-shows-strong-support-above-3900-level/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oliver Dale]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 10:26:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ethereum]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blockonomi.com/?p=108372</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>TLDR Ethereum has broken above $4,000 again, showing a 30% gain over the past month and 80.5% increase since December 2023 Bitcoin&#8217;s new all-time high of $107,822 on December 16, 2024 appears to be driving ETH&#8217;s upward momentum Trump&#8217;s pro-crypto stance and upcoming inauguration are contributing to positive market sentiment ETH is currently 17.8% below [...]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blockonomi.com/ethereum-eth-price-ethereum-shows-strong-support-above-3900-level/">Ethereum (ETH) Price: Ethereum Shows Strong Support Above $3,900 Level</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blockonomi.com">Blockonomi</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>TLDR</h2>
<ul>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Ethereum has broken above $4,000 again, showing a 30% gain over the past month and 80.5% increase since December 2023</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Bitcoin&#8217;s new all-time high of $107,822 on December 16, 2024 appears to be driving ETH&#8217;s upward momentum</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Trump&#8217;s pro-crypto stance and upcoming inauguration are contributing to positive market sentiment</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">ETH is currently 17.8% below its all-time high of $4,878.26 from November 2021</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">CoinCodex predicts ETH will reach a new peak of $5,094.65 by February 21, 2025, representing a potential 26.69% increase</li>
</ul>
<hr />
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words"><a href="https://watcher.guru/news/ethereum-hits-4000-again-will-eth-reclaim-its-all-time-high">Ethereum (ETH) has achieved another milestone in its price journey, breaking through the $4,000</a> barrier amid strong market conditions and growing investor confidence. The second-largest cryptocurrency by market capitalization has shown remarkable resilience, posting gains of 1.4% in daily trading and an impressive 30% increase over the past month.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The digital asset&#8217;s recent performance reflects broader market strength, with particularly notable gains over various timeframes. Weekly charts show an 8.1% increase, while the 14-day period demonstrates a 10.1% upward movement. Perhaps most striking is the year-over-year comparison, with ETH recording an 80.5% gain since December 2023.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Technical analysis reveals a bullish trend line forming with support at $3,940 on the hourly chart. <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/analysis/eth/ethereum-gears-up-4120/">The price action shows ETH trading above both the $4,000 psychological level and the 100-hourly Simple Moving Average,</a> indicating strong buyer presence in the market.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The current rally appears to be closely tied to Bitcoin&#8217;s recent performance, with BTC reaching a new all-time high of $107,822 on December 16, 2024. As the market leader, Bitcoin&#8217;s price movements often set the tone for the entire cryptocurrency market, and Ethereum has historically shown strong correlation with BTC&#8217;s upward trends.</p>
<figure id="attachment_108382" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-108382" style="width: 847px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-108382" src="https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-17-at-10-22-40-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko.png" alt="Ethereum Price on CoinGecko" width="847" height="631" srcset="https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-17-at-10-22-40-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko.png 847w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-17-at-10-22-40-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-300x223.png 300w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-17-at-10-22-40-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-768x572.png 768w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-17-at-10-22-40-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-50x37.png 50w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-17-at-10-22-40-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-150x112.png 150w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-17-at-10-22-40-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-450x335.png 450w" sizes="(max-width: 847px) 100vw, 847px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-108382" class="wp-caption-text">Ethereum Price on <a href="https://www.coingecko.com/en/coins/ethereum">CoinGecko</a></figcaption></figure>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Trading data indicates that Ethereum faces immediate resistance near the $4,070 level, corresponding to the 76.4% Fibonacci retracement level of the recent downward move from $4,107 to $3,946. A breakthrough above this level could open the path to test higher resistance points.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The next major resistance level stands at $4,120, followed by potential targets at $4,250 and $4,350. Market observers note that clearing these levels could potentially push ETH toward the $4,500 mark in the near term.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Support levels have established themselves at key points, with initial support near $3,980 and a stronger foundation at $3,940. These levels provide important price floors that could help maintain the current upward momentum.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The upcoming political transition appears to be playing a role in market sentiment. Donald Trump&#8217;s scheduled inauguration on January 20, 2025, has sparked optimism among crypto investors, given his administration&#8217;s pro-cryptocurrency stance.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Recent appointments, including a new SEC chair and White House crypto czar, have further boosted market confidence. These regulatory developments suggest a potentially more favorable environment for cryptocurrency adoption and growth.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Historical context shows that <a href="https://moneycheck.com/best-ethereum-casinos/">Ethereum</a> still trades below its all-time high of $4,878.26, recorded in November 2021. The current price represents a 17.8% gap from this peak, suggesting room for further upward movement.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Technical indicators present a positive outlook, with the hourly MACD gaining momentum in the bullish zone and the RSI holding above the 50 mark. These metrics typically suggest continued upward pressure on price.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">CoinCodex&#8217;s analysis projects optimistic targets for ETH, predicting a new all-time high of $5,094.65 by February 21, 2025. This forecast represents a potential increase of 26.69% from current levels.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The hourly chart patterns show ETH maintaining stability above key moving averages, with steady buying pressure evident in recent trading sessions. Volume indicators suggest growing market participation as prices push higher.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Trading activity has increased notably across major exchanges, indicating broader market engagement with ETH&#8217;s upward movement. This heightened activity often precedes sustained price trends.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Any pullbacks have found reliable support, with buyers stepping in at previously established support zones. This pattern of higher lows supports the overall bullish market structure.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Recent price action shows ETH successfully holding above the $4,000 level despite occasional tests of lower support. The ability to maintain this price point suggests strong buyer conviction at current levels.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The most recent data shows ETH trading at $4,020, with 24-hour trading volume reaching substantial levels across major cryptocurrency exchanges.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blockonomi.com/ethereum-eth-price-ethereum-shows-strong-support-above-3900-level/">Ethereum (ETH) Price: Ethereum Shows Strong Support Above $3,900 Level</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blockonomi.com">Blockonomi</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">108372</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Justin Sun Files Request for 53,000 ETH Withdrawal from Lido</title>
		<link>https://blockonomi.com/justin-sun-files-request-for-53000-eth-withdrawal-from-lido/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oliver Dale]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 09:45:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Ethereum]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blockonomi.com/?p=108269</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>TLDR Justin Sun has applied to withdraw 52,905 ETH (worth ~$209 million) from Lido, part of a larger accumulation strategy involving 392,474 ETH purchased between February and August Sun recently sold 29,920 ETH worth $119.7 million to HTX exchange after ETH reached $4,000 Current ETH price is at $3,961 with a 27% monthly gain and [...]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blockonomi.com/justin-sun-files-request-for-53000-eth-withdrawal-from-lido/">Justin Sun Files Request for 53,000 ETH Withdrawal from Lido</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blockonomi.com">Blockonomi</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>TLDR</h2>
<ul>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Justin Sun has applied to withdraw 52,905 ETH (worth ~$209 million) from Lido, part of a larger accumulation strategy involving 392,474 ETH purchased between February and August</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Sun recently sold 29,920 ETH worth $119.7 million to HTX exchange after ETH reached $4,000</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Current ETH price is at $3,961 with a 27% monthly gain and 2% 24-hour increase</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">ETH Futures Open Interest increased by 5%, suggesting strong market confidence</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Whale activity shows increased buying since ETH crossed $3,300, with some analysts projecting future price targets</li>
</ul>
<hr />
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Prominent crypto figure J<a href="https://coingape.com/tron-founder-justin-sun-to-bag-52-9k-ethereum-whats-happening/">ustin Sun is making waves in the Ethereum market with plans to acquire approximately 53,000 ETH</a> from Lido, according to recent reports from on-chain <a href="https://platform.spotonchain.ai/en/entity/278">analytics platform Spot On Chain.</a></p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The withdrawal request comes at a time when Ethereum&#8217;s price has maintained strong momentum, trading at $3,961 with a 2% increase over the past 24 hours. Trading volume has also shown robust growth, climbing 11% to reach $30.5 billion.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">This latest move by Sun is part of a broader pattern of Ethereum accumulation. Between February and August, the Tron founder reportedly amassed 392,474 ETH through three different wallets, representing an investment of approximately $1.19 billion.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The timing of Sun&#8217;s latest acquisition request has drawn particular attention from market observers, as it follows his recent sale of 29,920 ETH to the HTX exchange. That transaction, valued at roughly $119.7 million, occurred shortly after Ethereum&#8217;s price touched the $4,000 mark.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Market data suggests Sun&#8217;s investment strategy has been profitable thus far. His current ETH holdings show an estimated profit of $349 million, translating to a 29% return on investment. This performance aligns with Ethereum&#8217;s broader market strength, which has seen a monthly appreciation of 27%.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The cryptocurrency&#8217;s technical indicators have shown positive momentum. ETH Futures Open Interest has increased by approximately 5%, a metric that traditionally signals strong market confidence in the asset&#8217;s prospects.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">These developments occur against a backdrop of increased institutional interest in <a href="https://moneycheck.com/best-ethereum-casinos/">Ethereum</a>. Market analysts have noted a surge in whale activity, with large-scale buyers becoming more active since Ethereum crossed the $3,300 price level.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Sun&#8217;s trading activities have historically influenced market sentiment, and his latest moves are being closely monitored by traders and investors. The substantial size of his planned acquisition &#8211; 52,905 ETH worth approximately $209 million &#8211; represents a notable position in the market.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The cryptocurrency has demonstrated resilience in recent trading sessions, maintaining price levels above $3,900 despite various market fluctuations. In the past 24 hours, ETH reached a high of $4,020, showcasing its ability to sustain momentum near these price levels.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Trading volume metrics indicate healthy market participation, with sustained buying pressure supporting current price levels. The increase in trading activity suggests broad-based market interest rather than isolated large trades moving the market.</p>
<figure id="attachment_108270" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-108270" style="width: 847px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-108270" src="https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-16-at-09-43-06-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko.png" alt="Ethereum Price on CoinGecko" width="847" height="634" srcset="https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-16-at-09-43-06-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko.png 847w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-16-at-09-43-06-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-300x225.png 300w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-16-at-09-43-06-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-768x575.png 768w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-16-at-09-43-06-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-50x37.png 50w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-16-at-09-43-06-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-150x112.png 150w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-16-at-09-43-06-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-450x337.png 450w" sizes="(max-width: 847px) 100vw, 847px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-108270" class="wp-caption-text">Ethereum Price on <a href="https://www.coingecko.com/en/coins/ethereum">CoinGecko</a></figcaption></figure>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Technical analysis of Ethereum&#8217;s price action shows established support levels have held firm, while resistance near the $4,000 mark continues to be tested. The asset&#8217;s price stability at these levels has contributed to positive market sentiment.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Market data reveals consistent institutional involvement, with derivatives markets showing increased activity. The growth in ETH Futures Open Interest provides evidence of traders taking longer-term positions in the asset.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">On-chain metrics have remained robust, with network activity and transaction volumes supporting the current price levels. These fundamental indicators often serve as key measures of the network&#8217;s health and adoption.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Spot trading volumes across major exchanges have shown steady growth, indicating sustained market interest at current price levels. This broad-based participation suggests market depth has improved at higher price points.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The last 24 hours have seen Ethereum maintain its position above key technical levels, with price action suggesting continued buying pressure. Market order books show balanced trading activity, with both buying and selling pressure distributed across price ranges.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blockonomi.com/justin-sun-files-request-for-53000-eth-withdrawal-from-lido/">Justin Sun Files Request for 53,000 ETH Withdrawal from Lido</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blockonomi.com">Blockonomi</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">108269</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ethereum (ETH) Price: Bulls Target $4,000 After Breaking Key Resistance</title>
		<link>https://blockonomi.com/ethereum-eth-price-bulls-target-4000-after-breaking-key-resistance/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oliver Dale]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 11:23:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ethereum]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blockonomi.com/?p=108153</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>TLDR Ethereum has shown strong upward momentum, breaking above $3,750 and reaching a high of $3,988 A bullish trend line is forming with support at $3,840, suggesting continued upward potential The next major resistance levels are at $3,980 and $4,000, with potential targets at $4,150 and $4,320 Technical indicators including MACD and RSI show bullish [...]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blockonomi.com/ethereum-eth-price-bulls-target-4000-after-breaking-key-resistance/">Ethereum (ETH) Price: Bulls Target $4,000 After Breaking Key Resistance</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blockonomi.com">Blockonomi</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>TLDR</h2>
<ul>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Ethereum has shown strong upward momentum, breaking above $3,750 and reaching a high of $3,988</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">A bullish trend line is forming with support at $3,840, suggesting continued upward potential</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">The next major resistance levels are at $3,980 and $4,000, with potential targets at $4,150 and $4,320</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Technical indicators including MACD and RSI show bullish momentum</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Key support levels exist at $3,840, $3,750, and $3,665 if price retraces</li>
</ul>
<hr />
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words"><a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/analysis/eth/ethereum-price-aims-higher-4000/">Ethereum&#8217;s price movement has captured market attention as it steadily approaches the $4,000 mark, demonstrating strength in recent trading sessions.</a> The second-largest cryptocurrency by market capitalization has established multiple support levels above $3,800, suggesting a solid foundation for potential further gains.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">In recent hours, Ethereum successfully broke above the $3,750 resistance level, continuing its upward trajectory to reach a local high of $3,988. This move represents a clear break above several technical resistance levels that had previously constrained price action.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The price action shows particular strength above the $3,800 level, where traders have established a notable support zone. Technical analysis reveals a bullish trend line forming with support at $3,840, providing a base for potential future moves higher.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Trading data indicates that <a href="https://moneycheck.com/best-ethereum-casinos/">Ethereum&#8217;</a>s price currently sits above both the $3,800 mark and the 100-hourly Simple Moving Average, technical indicators that traders often use to gauge market momentum. This positioning suggests underlying strength in the current market structure.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Market participants have noted several key resistance levels that could influence future price action. The first major hurdle appears at $3,950, followed by a more substantial resistance zone near $3,980. Breaking above these levels could open the path to test the psychologically important $4,000 mark.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Should buyers succeed in pushing the price above $4,000, technical analysis suggests potential targets at $4,150 and $4,320. These levels represent the next major resistance zones where increased selling pressure might emerge.</p>
<figure id="attachment_108154" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-108154" style="width: 847px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-108154" src="https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-13-at-11-21-35-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko.png" alt="Ethereum Price on CoinGecko" width="847" height="629" srcset="https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-13-at-11-21-35-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko.png 847w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-13-at-11-21-35-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-300x223.png 300w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-13-at-11-21-35-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-768x570.png 768w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-13-at-11-21-35-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-50x37.png 50w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-13-at-11-21-35-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-150x111.png 150w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-13-at-11-21-35-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-450x334.png 450w" sizes="(max-width: 847px) 100vw, 847px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-108154" class="wp-caption-text">Ethereum Price on <a href="https://www.coingecko.com/en/coins/ethereum">CoinGecko</a></figcaption></figure>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">However, traders should note the presence of several support levels that could come into play if the price experiences a retracement. The first notable support sits at $3,840, coinciding with the bullish trend line identified in recent price action.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Below this, the $3,750 zone represents another crucial support level, corresponding to the 50% Fibonacci retracement level of the recent upward move from $3,527 to $3,988. This technical indicator often serves as a reference point for traders analyzing potential reversal levels.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Technical indicators currently support the bullish case, with the MACD showing increasing momentum in the positive zone. The Relative Strength Index (RSI) remains above the 50 mark, indicating healthy buying pressure in the market.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Trading volume analysis shows steady participation from market actors, suggesting genuine interest in the current price action rather than artificial movement. This volume profile adds credibility to the recent price advances.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The hourly chart reveals a pattern of higher lows, typically considered a bullish market characteristic. This pattern has remained intact throughout the recent price action, providing additional technical support for the upward trend.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">If the price fails to maintain its current trajectory, several additional support levels could come into play. These include the $3,665 zone and, in a more extensive pullback scenario, the $3,550 area. The $3,500 level represents a major support zone that traders are watching closely.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Recent price data shows consolidation near the $3,900 level, with traders apparently gathering strength for potential attempts at higher levels. The market has demonstrated an ability to hold gains, suggesting underlying buying pressure.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The current market structure includes multiple support levels, providing potential safety nets for any short-term price corrections. These technical factors contribute to the overall stability of the recent price advance.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The most recent price action shows Ethereum trading near $3,900, maintaining its position above key support levels while market participants assess the potential for further upward movement.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blockonomi.com/ethereum-eth-price-bulls-target-4000-after-breaking-key-resistance/">Ethereum (ETH) Price: Bulls Target $4,000 After Breaking Key Resistance</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blockonomi.com">Blockonomi</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">108153</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ethereum (ETH) Price: Approaches $4,000 as Van de Poppe Projects Higher Targets</title>
		<link>https://blockonomi.com/ethereum-eth-price-approaches-4000-as-van-de-poppe-projects-higher-targets/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oliver Dale]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 09:31:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ethereum]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blockonomi.com/?p=107989</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>TLDR ETH currently trading at $3,929.46 with a 7.39% daily increase and 2.17% weekly gain Van de Poppe predicts bull run to continue into 2025 if ETH breaks $3,800 resistance Strong support at $3,715 according to IOMAP metrics suggests buyer confidence Key resistance levels between $3,830-$4,274 with potential targets of $4,096 and $4,500 Critical support [...]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blockonomi.com/ethereum-eth-price-approaches-4000-as-van-de-poppe-projects-higher-targets/">Ethereum (ETH) Price: Approaches $4,000 as Van de Poppe Projects Higher Targets</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blockonomi.com">Blockonomi</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>TLDR</h2>
<ul>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">ETH currently trading at $3,929.46 with a 7.39% daily increase and 2.17% weekly gain</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Van de Poppe predicts bull run to continue into 2025 if ETH breaks $3,800 resistance</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Strong support at $3,715 according to IOMAP metrics suggests buyer confidence</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Key resistance levels between $3,830-$4,274 with potential targets of $4,096 and $4,500</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Critical support level at $3,505 must hold to maintain bullish outlook</li>
</ul>
<hr />
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Ethereum&#8217;s price momentum continues to build as the leading smart contract platform approaches the psychologically important $4,000 level. <a href="https://www.crypto-news-flash.com/ethereum-news-eth-bull-run-to-resume-and-last-into-2025-michael-van-de-poppe-says/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=ethereum-news-eth-bull-run-to-resume-and-last-into-2025-michael-van-de-poppe-says">Trading data shows ETH has gained over 7% in the past 24 hours, reaching $3,929.46 as buyers step in at crucial support levels.</a></p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The recent price action has caught the attention of veteran crypto analyst Michael van de Poppe, who sees the current consolidation phase as a healthy pullback within a larger upward trend. According to van de Poppe, ETH&#8217;s ability to maintain support above $3,715 signals strong buyer interest at current levels.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Technical indicators paint an optimistic picture for Ethereum&#8217;s near-term prospects. The In/Out of Money Around Price (IOMAP) metric reveals substantial buying activity clustering around the $3,715 price point, suggesting this level could serve as a springboard for future moves higher.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Market data shows ETH has posted impressive gains over multiple timeframes, with a 7.39% increase over the past day and 2.17% growth over the week. This steady appreciation comes despite some resistance encountered near the $4,000 mark.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr"><a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%24ETH&amp;src=ctag&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">$ETH</a> actually provides an excellent opportunity to accumulate. </p>
<p>Standard correction after testing a new resistance area. </p>
<p>I expect we&#39;ll continue to run from later this month into the new year. <a href="https://t.co/zFSwvtFvDH">pic.twitter.com/zFSwvtFvDH</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Michaël van de Poppe (@CryptoMichNL) <a href="https://twitter.com/CryptoMichNL/status/1866774172468236351?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 11, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Trading volume patterns indicate growing institutional interest in Ethereum. Professional traders appear to be using the recent consolidation phase as an opportunity to accumulate ETH at what they consider attractive price levels below $4,000.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Van de Poppe identifies several key price zones that could determine ETH&#8217;s trajectory in the coming months. The immediate resistance band lies between $3,830 and $4,274, with potential targets at $4,096 and $4,500 if these levels are breached decisively.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The current market structure suggests a continuation of the upward trend, provided<a href="https://moneycheck.com/best-ethereum-casinos/"> ETH</a> maintains support above $3,505. This level represents a crucial floor that bulls must defend to preserve the positive momentum.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Recent price action shows ETH finding steady support during dips, indicating healthy market dynamics. Buyers have consistently stepped in to absorb selling pressure, preventing any sustained moves below key support levels.</p>
<figure id="attachment_107990" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-107990" style="width: 847px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-107990" src="https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-12-at-09-27-43-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko.png" alt="Ethereum Price on CoinGecko" width="847" height="628" srcset="https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-12-at-09-27-43-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko.png 847w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-12-at-09-27-43-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-300x222.png 300w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-12-at-09-27-43-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-768x569.png 768w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-12-at-09-27-43-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-50x37.png 50w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-12-at-09-27-43-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-150x111.png 150w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-12-at-09-27-43-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-450x334.png 450w" sizes="(max-width: 847px) 100vw, 847px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-107990" class="wp-caption-text">Ethereum Price on <a href="https://www.coingecko.com/en/coins/ethereum">CoinGecko</a></figcaption></figure>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Looking at broader market indicators, Ethereum&#8217;s network metrics continue to show robust activity. Transaction volumes and active addresses remain elevated, supporting the case for sustained price appreciation.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Van de Poppe&#8217;s analysis suggests the current consolidation phase could set up ETH for an extended bull run lasting into 2025. This projection assumes the cryptocurrency can successfully break above the $3,800 resistance zone.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The analyst notes that while temporary pullbacks are normal within bull markets, the overall trend remains positive as long as ETH holds above $3,505. A break below this level could trigger a retreat toward $3,182.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Market participants appear to be positioning for further upside, with derivatives data showing increasing long positions at current price levels. This accumulation pattern often precedes sustained price moves higher.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Recent trading sessions have seen ETH repeatedly testing the $3,800 resistance level, suggesting building pressure for a potential breakout. The repeated tests of this level without sharp rejections indicate growing buyer confidence.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Order book data reveals strong bid support has formed in the $3,700-$3,800 range, providing a cushion against potential downside moves. This price floor appears well-defended by buyers looking to accumulate positions.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The most recent price data shows ETH trading at $3,929.46, maintaining its position above key moving averages and technical support levels as market participants await a potential break above $4,000.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blockonomi.com/ethereum-eth-price-approaches-4000-as-van-de-poppe-projects-higher-targets/">Ethereum (ETH) Price: Approaches $4,000 as Van de Poppe Projects Higher Targets</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blockonomi.com">Blockonomi</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">107989</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ethereum (ETH) Price Records $234M in Liquidations as Price Retreats from $4,000</title>
		<link>https://blockonomi.com/ethereum-eth-price-records-234m-in-liquidations-as-price-retreats-from-4000/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oliver Dale]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 11:14:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ethereum]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blockonomi.com/?p=107932</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>TLDR Ethereum tested $4,000 resistance level before experiencing a notable pullback to $3,621 Binance&#8217;s taker buy-sell ratio turned negative, indicating increased retail selling pressure ETH trading volume rose from $60B to $72B despite price decrease, suggesting active sell-offs Total crypto market liquidations reached $1.58B, with ETH accounting for $234.72M Institutional ETF demand remains strong, helping [...]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blockonomi.com/ethereum-eth-price-records-234m-in-liquidations-as-price-retreats-from-4000/">Ethereum (ETH) Price Records $234M in Liquidations as Price Retreats from $4,000</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blockonomi.com">Blockonomi</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>TLDR</h2>
<ul>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Ethereum tested $4,000 resistance level before experiencing a notable pullback to $3,621</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Binance&#8217;s taker buy-sell ratio turned negative, indicating increased retail selling pressure</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">ETH trading volume rose from $60B to $72B despite price decrease, suggesting active sell-offs</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Total crypto market liquidations reached $1.58B, with ETH accounting for $234.72M</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Institutional ETF demand remains strong, helping offset retail selling pressure</li>
</ul>
<hr />
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words"><a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/news/ethereum/ethereum-battles-bearish-retail-sentiment-amid-surging-etf-demand/">Ethereum (ETH) has pulled back from the $4,000 resistance level, currently trading at $3,621</a>, marking a 6% decrease in the past 24 hours. The retreat comes as retail traders on Binance show increased selling pressure, while institutional interest through ETF products remains robust.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Data from cryptocurrency exchanges reveals a sharp decline in Ethereum&#8217;s market capitalization, which has dropped by over $40 billion from its recent peak. The total market cap fell from $490 billion last Friday to $434 billion at present, highlighting the scale of the current correction.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Despite the price decrease, Ethereum&#8217;s daily trading volume has shown an opposite trend. Volume has increased from $60 billion on December 6 to $72 billion currently, suggesting active market participation during the downturn. Market analysts attribute this volume surge primarily to selling activity.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words"><a href="https://cryptoquant.com/insights/quicktake/67578758494b0e68b488a3dd-Binance-ETH-investors-turned-bearish">CryptoQuant analyst</a> Darkfost reports that Binance&#8217;s taker buy-sell ratio for Ethereum turned negative as the price approached $4,000. This metric indicates that traders on the platform have largely adopted a selling stance, particularly since the beginning of November.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The market has witnessed substantial liquidations across the cryptocurrency space. According to Coinglass data, the past 24 hours saw 526,828 traders liquidated, with total liquidations reaching $1.58 billion. Ethereum-specific liquidations accounted for $234.72 million of this total.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Breaking down the ETH liquidations further, long positions made up the majority at $208.83 million, while short positions recorded losses of $25.89 million. These figures underscore the market&#8217;s current directional bias and the risks faced by leveraged traders.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Trading patterns on Binance, one of the largest cryptocurrency exchanges, show retail traders have maintained their bearish stance throughout the recent price movement. This selling pressure has created consistent resistance around the $4,000 price level.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">However, institutional interest tells a different story. Demand for <a href="https://moneycheck.com/best-ethereum-casinos/">Ethereum</a> Exchange-Traded Funds (ETFs) continues to show strength, providing a counterbalance to retail selling pressure. This institutional backing has helped maintain support levels despite the current correction.</p>
<figure id="attachment_107933" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-107933" style="width: 847px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-107933" src="https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-11-at-10-55-09-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko.png" alt="Ethereum Price on CoinGecko" width="847" height="628" srcset="https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-11-at-10-55-09-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko.png 847w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-11-at-10-55-09-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-300x222.png 300w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-11-at-10-55-09-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-768x569.png 768w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-11-at-10-55-09-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-50x37.png 50w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-11-at-10-55-09-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-150x111.png 150w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-11-at-10-55-09-Ethereum-Price-ETH-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-450x334.png 450w" sizes="(max-width: 847px) 100vw, 847px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-107933" class="wp-caption-text">Ethereum Price on<a href="https://www.coingecko.com/en/coins/ethereum"> CoinGecko</a></figcaption></figure>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The contrast between retail and institutional behavior highlights a divergence in market sentiment across different trader categories. While smaller traders appear to be taking profits, larger institutional players continue to accumulate positions through regulated investment products.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Technical indicators suggest the current price action represents a test of key support levels. The movement below $4,000 has triggered increased selling pressure, though some market participants view this as a healthy correction within a broader upward trend.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Market data indicates that the selling pressure intensified after Ethereum failed to maintain momentum above the $3,900 level. This technical resistance point has become a focal point for traders monitoring price action.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The cryptocurrency&#8217;s price movement has prompted various responses from market participants. While some traders have closed positions, others view the current levels as potential entry points, particularly given the continued institutional interest.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Looking at order book data, significant support has formed around the $3,500 level, while resistance remains concentrated near the recent high of $4,000. These price points have become key areas of interest for market participants.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Recent data shows that exchange inflows and outflows have remained relatively balanced, suggesting that despite the price correction, there hasn&#8217;t been a mass exodus of ETH from trading platforms.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The market has recorded over $72 billion in daily trading volume, indicating active participation from both buyers and sellers. This elevated trading activity suggests high market engagement during the current price movement.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blockonomi.com/ethereum-eth-price-records-234m-in-liquidations-as-price-retreats-from-4000/">Ethereum (ETH) Price Records $234M in Liquidations as Price Retreats from $4,000</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blockonomi.com">Blockonomi</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">107932</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bitwise Report: Bitcoin, Ethereum, and Solana Expected to Reach New Highs in 2025</title>
		<link>https://blockonomi.com/bitwise-report-bitcoin-ethereum-and-solana-expected-to-reach-new-highs-in-2025/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oliver Dale]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 09:39:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ethereum]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blockonomi.com/?p=107887</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>TLDR Bitcoin hit new ATH of $104,000 in 2024, up 141.72% YTD, driven by spot ETF launches totaling $33.56B in assets Crypto-friendly Trump administration expected to establish Bitcoin strategic reserve and reform SEC policies Bitwise predicts Bitcoin could reach $200,000-$500,000, ETH $7,000, and SOL $750 by 2025 Major cryptocurrencies outperformed traditional assets in 2024: SOL [...]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blockonomi.com/bitwise-report-bitcoin-ethereum-and-solana-expected-to-reach-new-highs-in-2025/">Bitwise Report: Bitcoin, Ethereum, and Solana Expected to Reach New Highs in 2025</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blockonomi.com">Blockonomi</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>TLDR</h2>
<ul>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Bitcoin hit new ATH of $104,000 in 2024, up 141.72% YTD, driven by spot ETF launches totaling $33.56B in assets</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Crypto-friendly Trump administration expected to establish Bitcoin strategic reserve and reform SEC policies</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Bitwise predicts Bitcoin could reach $200,000-$500,000, ETH $7,000, and SOL $750 by 2025</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Major cryptocurrencies outperformed traditional assets in 2024: SOL up 127.71%, XRP up 285.23%, ETH up 75.77%</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Crypto-related stocks showed strong performance: MicroStrategy up 525.39%, Coinbase up 97.57%</li>
</ul>
<hr />
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Cryptocurrency asset manager<a href="https://s3.us-east-1.amazonaws.com/static.bitwiseinvestments.com/Research/Bitwise-The-Year-Ahead-10-Crypto-Predictions-for-2025.pdf"> Bitwise has released a comprehensive report</a> predicting record-breaking valuations for major digital assets by 2025, backed by data showing strong institutional adoption and regulatory developments in 2024.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words"><a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/bitcoin-news/bitwise-forecast-bitcoin-ethereum-and-solana-poised-for-record-highs-in-2025/">The cryptocurrency market demonstrated robust growth in 2024, with Bitcoin reaching $104,000, marking a 141.72% increase year-to-date.</a> This surge coincided with the launch of spot Bitcoin ETFs in the United States, which accumulated $33.56 billion in assets.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Other cryptocurrencies showed similar upward momentum. Solana posted gains of 127.71%, while XRP experienced a 285.23% increase. Ethereum, despite lagging behind its peers, still achieved a 75.77% rise in value.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The cryptocurrency market&#8217;s strength extended beyond digital assets to crypto-related equities. MicroStrategy, a business intelligence company known for its Bitcoin holdings, saw its stock price surge by 525.39%. Cryptocurrency exchange Coinbase also performed well, with its shares rising 97.57%.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">These gains outpaced traditional financial markets, with the S&amp;P 500 returning 28.07%, gold increasing by 27.65%, and bonds yielding 3.40% during the same period.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The regulatory landscape showed marked improvement throughout 2024. The success of crypto-friendly candidates in U.S. elections created a more favorable environment for the industry. President-elect Donald Trump&#8217;s campaign embraced cryptocurrencies, including plans to establish a strategic Bitcoin reserve.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The appointment of Scott Bessent as Treasury Secretary further reinforced positive sentiment, given his previous statements supporting cryptocurrency as a vehicle for freedom. These developments contributed to the market&#8217;s upward trajectory.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Looking ahead to 2025, Bitwise&#8217;s research team describes the period as the &#8220;Golden Age of Crypto.&#8221; Their optimistic outlook stems from increasing institutional adoption, technological advances in blockchain, and expected stimulus measures from major central banks.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The report specifically focuses on Bitcoin, Ethereum, and Solana, which they term the &#8220;magnificent three.&#8221; These assets are expected to maintain their strong performance relative to traditional investments.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">For <a href="https://moneycheck.com/best-bitcoin-casinos/">Bitcoin</a>, Bitwise projects potential prices of $200,000 to $500,000. This forecast considers continued inflows into Bitcoin ETFs and the supply reduction from the April 2024 halving event. The proposed U.S. government strategic reserve of one million Bitcoins could further drive prices upward.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words"><a href="https://moneycheck.com/best-ethereum-casinos/">Ethereum</a> faced challenges in 2024 as investors focused on Bitcoin and faster networks. However, Bitwise expects a revival in 2025, projecting a new all-time high of $7,000. This outlook is based on growing activity on Layer 2 solutions like Base and Starknet, anticipated spot Ethereum ETF inflows, and increased stablecoin and tokenization projects.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words"><a href="https://moneycheck.com/best-solana-casinos/">Solana&#8217;s</a> recovery from the 2022 market downturn impressed investors, with its 2024 surge partly driven by memecoin activity. Bitwise predicts continued ecosystem growth beyond memecoins, forecasting a new high of $750 per SOL.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The cryptocurrency market&#8217;s current state shows consolidation, with Bitcoin trading at $96,000, Ethereum at $3,662, and Solana at $218.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The April 2024 Bitcoin halving event remains a key factor in these projections, as it will reduce the rate of new Bitcoin creation and potentially increase scarcity in the market.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">These forecasts align with broader market trends showing increased institutional participation and mainstream adoption of cryptocurrencies through regulated investment vehicles.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blockonomi.com/bitwise-report-bitcoin-ethereum-and-solana-expected-to-reach-new-highs-in-2025/">Bitwise Report: Bitcoin, Ethereum, and Solana Expected to Reach New Highs in 2025</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blockonomi.com">Blockonomi</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">107887</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
