<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Bitcoin News &amp; Updates: Latest Live Info about Bitcoin from Blockonomi</title>
	<atom:link href="https://blockonomi.com/bitcoin/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://blockonomi.com/bitcoin/</link>
	<description>Cryptocurrency News &#38; Your Guide to the Blockchain Economy</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 11:14:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.7.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/fav-50x50.png</url>
	<title>Bitcoin News &amp; Updates: Latest Live Info about Bitcoin from Blockonomi</title>
	<link>https://blockonomi.com/bitcoin/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">134176212</site>	<item>
		<title>ARK Invest Sells $3.9M in Coinbase Shares Following Bitcoin Price Drop</title>
		<link>https://blockonomi.com/ark-invest-sells-3-9m-in-coinbase-shares-following-bitcoin-price-drop/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oliver Dale]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 11:14:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blockonomi.com/?p=108761</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>TLDR ARK Invest sold $3.9 million worth of Coinbase shares (13,780 shares) amid market decline Bitcoin hit all-time high of $108,135 before dropping to $97,430 Federal Reserve&#8217;s hawkish stance on 2025 interest rates triggered market correction ARK still maintains substantial Coinbase position with 2.45 million shares ($672 million) Market decline affected broader crypto ecosystem with [...]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blockonomi.com/ark-invest-sells-3-9m-in-coinbase-shares-following-bitcoin-price-drop/">ARK Invest Sells $3.9M in Coinbase Shares Following Bitcoin Price Drop</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blockonomi.com">Blockonomi</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>TLDR</h2>
<ul>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">ARK Invest sold $3.9 million worth of Coinbase shares (13,780 shares) amid market decline</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Bitcoin hit all-time high of $108,135 before dropping to $97,430</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Federal Reserve&#8217;s hawkish stance on 2025 interest rates triggered market correction</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">ARK still maintains substantial Coinbase position with 2.45 million shares ($672 million)</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Market decline affected broader crypto ecosystem with Ethereum dropping 12%</li>
</ul>
<hr />
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The cryptocurrency market experienced a notable correction this week, with <a href="https://decrypt.co/297681/cathie-wood-ark-invest-sells-coinbase-stock">Bitcoin retreating from its new all-time high as major investment firm ARK Invest adjusted its crypto-related holdings.</a> The market movement came amid broader reactions to Federal Reserve commentary about future interest rate policies.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">ARK Invest, led by Cathie Wood, sold 13,780 shares of Coinbase stock (NASDAQ: COIN) worth approximately $3.9 million on Wednesday. The sale was executed through the firm&#8217;s Ark Fintech Innovation ETF (ARKF) as part of its portfolio rebalancing strategy.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The timing of the sale coincided with a broader market decline that saw Coinbase&#8217;s stock price drop to $274 per share, representing a 2% decrease over the day and a 13% decline over five days. Despite the recent sale, ARK Invest maintains a substantial position in Coinbase, holding over 2.45 million shares valued at $672 million.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The market correction followed Bitcoin&#8217;s achievement of a new all-time high of $108,135 on Tuesday, according to data from CoinGecko. The leading cryptocurrency&#8217;s price has since declined to $97,430, marking a nearly 4% decrease over the last 24 hours.</p>
<figure id="attachment_108693" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-108693" style="width: 847px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-108693" src="https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-09-08-18-Bitcoin-Price-BTC-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko.png" alt="Bitcoin Price on CoinGecko" width="847" height="627" srcset="https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-09-08-18-Bitcoin-Price-BTC-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko.png 847w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-09-08-18-Bitcoin-Price-BTC-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-300x222.png 300w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-09-08-18-Bitcoin-Price-BTC-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-768x569.png 768w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-09-08-18-Bitcoin-Price-BTC-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-50x37.png 50w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-09-08-18-Bitcoin-Price-BTC-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-150x111.png 150w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-09-08-18-Bitcoin-Price-BTC-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-450x333.png 450w" sizes="(max-width: 847px) 100vw, 847px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-108693" class="wp-caption-text">Bitcoin Price on <a href="https://www.coingecko.com/en/coins/bitcoin">CoinGecko</a></figcaption></figure>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Federal Reserve Chair Jerome Powell&#8217;s recent speech played a central role in the market&#8217;s directional shift. Powell&#8217;s comments suggested a more conservative approach to interest rate cuts in 2025 than many market participants had anticipated, leading to widespread price adjustments across both crypto and traditional financial markets.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The impact of the correction extended beyond<a href="https://moneycheck.com/best-bitcoin-casinos/"> Bitcoin</a>, affecting other major cryptocurrencies in the ecosystem. Ethereum, the second-largest cryptocurrency by market capitalization, experienced a steeper decline, dropping by approximately 12% during the correction period.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The recent market movements come during a year that has seen substantial growth in crypto asset prices, particularly following the November 5 election of Donald Trump. The former president&#8217;s campaign promises regarding reduced regulation and support for the digital asset industry had previously contributed to positive market sentiment.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">This week&#8217;s sale marks another instance of ARK Invest&#8217;s active management of its Coinbase position. The investment firm has previously made similar moves, including a larger sale of nearly $52 million worth of shares in March as part of its portfolio management strategy.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The current market correction represents a departure from the recent upward trend that saw Bitcoin and other crypto assets reach new price levels. The leading cryptocurrency&#8217;s price movement from its peak above $108,000 to current levels below $98,000 highlights the market&#8217;s continued volatility.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">These price fluctuations occur against a backdrop of increased institutional interest in cryptocurrency markets. Coinbase, as America&#8217;s largest crypto exchange, has served as a barometer for institutional engagement with digital assets since its public listing in 2021.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Market participants have noted the correlation between cryptocurrency prices and broader economic indicators, particularly the Federal Reserve&#8217;s monetary policy decisions. The recent price action demonstrates how traditional financial market factors continue to influence crypto asset valuations.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The correction&#8217;s timing, occurring during the pre-holiday period, has led some market observers to monitor whether end-of-year trading patterns might influence price action. The reduced trading volumes typical of holiday periods can sometimes lead to increased price volatility.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Trump&#8217;s promised administration appointments of Silicon Valley tech figures and his stated intentions regarding digital asset industry support remain factors in longer-term market considerations. However, the immediate market response to Federal Reserve policy indicators suggests monetary policy continues to be a primary driver of short-term price action.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">ARK Invest&#8217;s portfolio adjustment comes as part of their regular rebalancing activities, with the firm maintaining its position as one of the largest institutional investors in Coinbase. The investment firm&#8217;s continued substantial holding in the crypto exchange indicates their long-term perspective on the digital asset sector.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The current price levels show Bitcoin trading at $97,430, with the overall crypto market experiencing varying degrees of correction across different assets. This price action follows a period of sustained growth that saw multiple cryptocurrencies reach new price milestones.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blockonomi.com/ark-invest-sells-3-9m-in-coinbase-shares-following-bitcoin-price-drop/">ARK Invest Sells $3.9M in Coinbase Shares Following Bitcoin Price Drop</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blockonomi.com">Blockonomi</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">108761</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bitcoin ETF Momentum Breaks: FBTC Posts $208M Withdrawal in Market Shake-up</title>
		<link>https://blockonomi.com/bitcoin-etf-momentum-breaks-fbtc-posts-208m-withdrawal-in-market-shake-up/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oliver Dale]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 09:29:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blockonomi.com/?p=108702</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>TLDR US Bitcoin ETFs experienced unprecedented single-day outflows of $672-680 million, breaking a 15-day streak of positive inflows Fidelity&#8217;s FBTC led the decline with $208.5 million in outflows, followed by substantial withdrawals from Grayscale and ARK funds Bitcoin price dropped below $96,000, representing a 4% decline over 24 hours amid broader market turbulence Federal Reserve&#8217;s [...]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blockonomi.com/bitcoin-etf-momentum-breaks-fbtc-posts-208m-withdrawal-in-market-shake-up/">Bitcoin ETF Momentum Breaks: FBTC Posts $208M Withdrawal in Market Shake-up</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blockonomi.com">Blockonomi</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>TLDR</h2>
<ul>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">US Bitcoin ETFs experienced unprecedented single-day outflows of $672-680 million, breaking a 15-day streak of positive inflows</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Fidelity&#8217;s FBTC led the decline with $208.5 million in outflows, followed by substantial withdrawals from Grayscale and ARK funds</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Bitcoin price dropped below $96,000, representing a 4% decline over 24 hours amid broader market turbulence</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Federal Reserve&#8217;s hawkish stance on future rate cuts triggered the market response, with fewer cuts planned for 2025</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Despite the sell-off, WisdomTree&#8217;s BTCW remained positive with $2 million in inflows, while trading volume increased to $6.31 billion</li>
</ul>
<hr />
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The United States Bitcoin ETF market experienced its largest single-day outflow in history on<a href="https://crypto.news/bitcoin-etfs-record-680m-outflows-as-btc-dips-below-96k/"> December 19, 2024, as investors withdrew approximately $680 million from various funds.</a> This massive withdrawal ended a 15-day streak of positive inflows that had brought over $6.7 billion into these investment vehicles.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Fidelity&#8217;s Bitcoin Fund (FBTC) bore the brunt of the exodus, recording outflows of $208.55 million. This marked the largest single-day withdrawal for any Bitcoin ETF since their introduction to the market. The Grayscale Bitcoin Mini Trust followed closely behind, with investors pulling out $188.6 million from the fund.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">ARK 21Shares&#8217; ARKB also faced substantial withdrawals, losing $108.35 million in a single trading session. The widespread nature of the outflows became apparent as Grayscale&#8217;s GBTC saw $87.86 million exit the fund during the same period.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The smaller players in the Bitcoin ETF space weren&#8217;t spared from the selling pressure. Bitwise&#8217;s BITB registered outflows of $43.61 million, while Invesco Galaxy&#8217;s BTCO saw $25.97 million leave the fund. VanEck&#8217;s HODL and Valkyrie&#8217;s BRRR experienced more modest outflows of $10.91 million and $8.19 million, respectively.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">In a notable exception to the overall trend, WisdomTree&#8217;s BTCW managed to attract $2.05 million in new investments. This small victory stood out against the backdrop of widespread withdrawals across the sector. BlackRock&#8217;s iShares Bitcoin Trust (IBIT) and two other Bitcoin ETFs reported no changes in their flow figures for the day.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The timing of these outflows coincided with Bitcoin&#8217;s price dropping below the $96,000 mark, representing a 4.4% decline. The cryptocurrency traded at $96,751 at the time of reporting, reflecting broader market uncertainty.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Despite the substantial outflows, trading activity in Bitcoin ETFs showed increased engagement from market participants. The total trading volume reached $6.31 billion, marking an improvement from the previous day&#8217;s figure of $5.86 billion.</p>
<figure id="attachment_108704" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-108704" style="width: 1000px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-108704" src="https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-09-24-37-Bitcoin-ETF-Flow-USm-–-Farside-Investors.png" alt="Bitcoin ETF Flow Farside Investors" width="1000" height="788" srcset="https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-09-24-37-Bitcoin-ETF-Flow-USm-–-Farside-Investors.png 1000w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-09-24-37-Bitcoin-ETF-Flow-USm-–-Farside-Investors-300x236.png 300w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-09-24-37-Bitcoin-ETF-Flow-USm-–-Farside-Investors-768x605.png 768w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-09-24-37-Bitcoin-ETF-Flow-USm-–-Farside-Investors-50x39.png 50w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-09-24-37-Bitcoin-ETF-Flow-USm-–-Farside-Investors-150x118.png 150w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-09-24-37-Bitcoin-ETF-Flow-USm-–-Farside-Investors-450x355.png 450w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-108704" class="wp-caption-text">Bitcoin ETF Flow<a href="https://farside.co.uk/btc/"> Farside Investors</a></figcaption></figure>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The catalyst for this market movement appeared to be the Federal Reserve&#8217;s latest interest rate decision and subsequent commentary. While the Fed implemented an expected 0.25% rate cut, bringing the year&#8217;s total reduction to 1%, their forward guidance proved less accommodative than many investors had hoped.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Fed officials indicated a more cautious approach to future rate cuts, announcing plans for only two additional reductions in 2025. This conservative stance contrasted with more optimistic market expectations, leading to a reassessment of investment positions across various asset classes.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The impact extended beyond<a href="https://moneycheck.com/best-bitcoin-casinos/"> Bitcoin</a> ETFs, affecting the broader cryptocurrency market. The total crypto market capitalization experienced a 4.5% decline, settling at $3.51 trillion. This movement highlighted the interconnected nature of traditional and digital asset markets.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Ethereum ETFs also felt the effects of the market downturn, recording outflows of $60.47 million. This ended an 18-day streak of positive inflows for these funds. Grayscale&#8217;s ETHE led the Ethereum ETF outflows with $58.13 million in withdrawals.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Other Ethereum funds showed mixed results. Bitwise&#8217;s ETHW, Grayscale Ethereum Mini Trust, and Invesco&#8217;s QETH reported outflows of $6.78 million, $3.18 million, and $2.36 million respectively. However, Fidelity&#8217;s FETH and VanEck&#8217;s ETHV provided some counterbalance, attracting inflows of $5.05 million and $4.94 million.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The market&#8217;s reaction demonstrates the growing integration between traditional financial markets and cryptocurrency investments. The Federal Reserve&#8217;s monetary policy decisions now clearly influence behavior in both sectors, showing the maturing nature of digital asset markets.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Trading data revealed that institutional investors played a major role in the day&#8217;s movements. The increased trading volume suggests active portfolio rebalancing rather than passive selling, indicating strategic rather than panic-driven decisions.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Current market metrics show Bitcoin trading at $97,000, representing a 4% decrease over the past 24 hours according to the latest data. The cryptocurrency market continues to process the implications of the Federal Reserve&#8217;s policy stance, with investors adjusting their positions accordingly.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blockonomi.com/bitcoin-etf-momentum-breaks-fbtc-posts-208m-withdrawal-in-market-shake-up/">Bitcoin ETF Momentum Breaks: FBTC Posts $208M Withdrawal in Market Shake-up</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blockonomi.com">Blockonomi</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">108702</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bitcoin (BTC) Price: Retreats to $97K Following Federal Reserve&#8217;s Hawkish Stance</title>
		<link>https://blockonomi.com/bitcoin-btc-price-bitcoin-btc-retreats-to-97k-following-federal-reserves-hawkish-stance/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oliver Dale]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 09:16:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blockonomi.com/?p=108691</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>TLDR Bitcoin price dropped below $98,000 following the Federal Reserve&#8217;s more hawkish than expected policy outlook Fed projects fewer interest rate cuts in 2025 than previously indicated Bitcoin fell from near record levels to $97,000, with a brief recovery above $102,000 Other cryptocurrencies including Ethereum saw declines of 5% or more Market participants are recalibrating [...]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blockonomi.com/bitcoin-btc-price-bitcoin-btc-retreats-to-97k-following-federal-reserves-hawkish-stance/">Bitcoin (BTC) Price: Retreats to $97K Following Federal Reserve&#8217;s Hawkish Stance</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blockonomi.com">Blockonomi</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>TLDR</h2>
<ul>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Bitcoin price dropped below $98,000 following the Federal Reserve&#8217;s more hawkish than expected policy outlook</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Fed projects fewer interest rate cuts in 2025 than previously indicated</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Bitcoin fell from near record levels to $97,000, with a brief recovery above $102,000</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Other cryptocurrencies including Ethereum saw declines of 5% or more</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Market participants are recalibrating expectations based on Fed&#8217;s stance on maintaining tighter monetary conditions</li>
</ul>
<hr />
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words"><a href="https://bravenewcoin.com/insights/bitcoin-drops-to-97000-following-feds-hawkish-stance">Bitcoin&#8217;s price experienced a sharp decline to $97,000 on Thursday as markets processed the Federal Reserve&#8217;s latest policy announcement.</a> The move came after the central bank delivered its anticipated quarter-point rate reduction but surprised investors with a more conservative outlook for future cuts.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The cryptocurrency market had been riding high in recent weeks, with Bitcoin approaching record levels. However, the Federal Reserve&#8217;s updated projections for 2025 showed fewer planned rate reductions than previously indicated, causing a broad market adjustment.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Trading activity intensified immediately following the Fed&#8217;s announcement. Bitcoin&#8217;s price quickly moved below the $100,000 mark, though it managed to recover briefly above $102,000 before settling around $97,000 during afternoon trading sessions.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The Federal Reserve&#8217;s quarter-point reduction to its benchmark interest rate had been widely expected by market participants. However, the accompanying policy statement and economic projections painted a picture of a central bank determined to maintain a measured approach to monetary policy.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Fed Chair Jerome Powell&#8217;s comments during the post-meeting press conference reinforced this cautious stance. Powell emphasized the importance of maintaining control over inflation while acknowledging the progress made in recent months toward the Fed&#8217;s long-term goals.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The impact of the Fed&#8217;s announcement extended beyond Bitcoin.<a href="https://moneycheck.com/best-ethereum-casinos/"> Ethereum</a>, which holds the second-largest market capitalization in the cryptocurrency space, recorded a decline exceeding 5%. This movement highlighted the broader market&#8217;s sensitivity to monetary policy decisions.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Other cryptocurrencies experienced even steeper declines. Several major altcoins saw double-digit percentage drops as traders adjusted their positions. The so-called &#8220;meme&#8221; tokens, typically more volatile than established cryptocurrencies, faced particularly sharp selloffs.</p>
<figure id="attachment_108693" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-108693" style="width: 847px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-108693" src="https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-09-08-18-Bitcoin-Price-BTC-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko.png" alt="Bitcoin Price on CoinGecko" width="847" height="627" srcset="https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-09-08-18-Bitcoin-Price-BTC-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko.png 847w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-09-08-18-Bitcoin-Price-BTC-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-300x222.png 300w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-09-08-18-Bitcoin-Price-BTC-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-768x569.png 768w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-09-08-18-Bitcoin-Price-BTC-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-50x37.png 50w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-09-08-18-Bitcoin-Price-BTC-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-150x111.png 150w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-20-at-09-08-18-Bitcoin-Price-BTC-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-450x333.png 450w" sizes="(max-width: 847px) 100vw, 847px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-108693" class="wp-caption-text">Bitcoin Price on <a href="https://www.coingecko.com/en/coins/bitcoin">CoinGecko</a></figcaption></figure>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Market analysts pointed to the relationship between interest rate expectations and cryptocurrency valuations. Higher interest rates traditionally make speculative assets less attractive to investors, as the opportunity cost of holding non-yielding assets increases.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Trading volumes across major cryptocurrency exchanges surged during the price movement. This increased activity reflected the market&#8217;s rush to reposition portfolios in light of the Fed&#8217;s updated policy path.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Technical analysts noted several key price levels that came into focus during the decline. The $100,000 mark served as a psychological barrier, while the $97,000 level emerged as a point of price stability during the afternoon trading session.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The cryptocurrency market&#8217;s reaction appeared more pronounced than that of traditional financial markets, though stocks and other risk assets also showed sensitivity to the Fed&#8217;s announcement. This heightened reaction in crypto markets underscored the sector&#8217;s continued correlation with broader monetary policy shifts.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Derivatives markets also reflected the changing sentiment.<a href="https://moneycheck.com/best-bitcoin-casinos/"> Bitcoin</a> futures contracts saw increased trading activity, while options markets registered growing demand for downside protection.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Historical data suggests that Bitcoin has often displayed volatility around Federal Reserve policy announcements. However, the scale of this move caught some market participants off guard, given the recent strength in cryptocurrency prices.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Market makers reported that liquidations of leveraged positions contributed to the price movement. As Bitcoin&#8217;s price declined, automated trading systems triggered the closure of long positions, adding to the downward pressure.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The price movement occurred against a backdrop of strong institutional interest in Bitcoin. Recent months had seen increased adoption by traditional financial institutions, though this trend appeared temporarily overshadowed by the immediate market reaction to the Fed&#8217;s stance.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blockonomi.com/bitcoin-btc-price-bitcoin-btc-retreats-to-97k-following-federal-reserves-hawkish-stance/">Bitcoin (BTC) Price: Retreats to $97K Following Federal Reserve&#8217;s Hawkish Stance</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blockonomi.com">Blockonomi</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">108691</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bitcoin&#8217;s Fall Below $100k Sparks Renewed &#8216;Buy the Dip&#8217; Discussions: Santiment</title>
		<link>https://blockonomi.com/bitcoins-fall-below-100k-sparks-renewed-buy-the-dip-discussions-santiment/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nicholas Say]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 09:04:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blockonomi.com/?p=108681</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Even as Bitcoin sinks below $100,000, the cryptocurrency market is buzzing with “buy the dip” sentiment. Data from blockchain analysis platform Santiment reveals that online discussions about buying the dip are at an eight-month high, which indicates that many investors see the recent sell-off as a buying opportunity. The Crypto Fear and Greed Index is [...]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blockonomi.com/bitcoins-fall-below-100k-sparks-renewed-buy-the-dip-discussions-santiment/">Bitcoin&#8217;s Fall Below $100k Sparks Renewed &#8216;Buy the Dip&#8217; Discussions: Santiment</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blockonomi.com">Blockonomi</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Even as Bitcoin sinks below $100,000, the cryptocurrency market is <a href="https://cointelegraph.com/news/crypto-social-media-mentions-buy-the-dip-surges-bitcoin-100k-price-level-santiment">buzzing with “buy the dip”</a> sentiment. Data from blockchain analysis platform Santiment reveals that online discussions about buying the dip are at an eight-month high, which indicates that many investors see the recent sell-off as a buying opportunity.</p>
<p>The Crypto Fear and Greed Index is still in the greed zone. With a lot of people looking for big gains, there could be more pain ahead.</p>
<blockquote><p><em>“The ratio of crypto discussions that are about buying crypto&#8217;s dip has reached its highest level in over 8 months. The last time we saw the crowd nearly this enthusiastic about dip buying was the major crash on August 4th. Since that time, Bitcoin&#8217;s market cap is +81% higher,”</em> Santiment noted in a statement.</p></blockquote>
<p>Data shows a clear link between major Bitcoin price drops and increased “buying the dip” sentiment on social media. The crypto Trump rally was great, but it looks like it is over.</p>
<h2>Lower Prices to Come?</h2>
<p>As reported, the “social dominance score” which tracks mentions of “buying the dip” on social channels climbed to 0.061, the highest level since April 12. That day, Bitcoin fell below $70,000 and extended its correction to around $63,000 the following day.</p>
<p>Data also shows a similar spike in “buying the dip” talks on August 4, when Bitcoin sank under $60,000 and slid further to around $53,000.</p>
<p>Bitcoin began a sharp price correction on Thursday, declining from $102,000 to below $96,000. It is currently trading at $97,700, reflecting a 3.6% decrease over the past 24 hours. Despite this recent downturn, the flagship cryptocurrency still shows a 128% gain year-to-date, per CoinGecko.</p>
<p>Altcoins are faring even worse. Many cryptocurrencies posted two-digit losses in a day. Over the past 24 hours, Dogecoin (DOGE) shed 12%, Ether fell nearly 8% to $3,400, and Solana plummeted 8.6% to $193. Ripple (XRP), meanwhile, saw a decline of 3%.</p>
<h2>Rate Worries</h2>
<p>Market turbulence intensified following the Federal Reserve&#8217;s Wednesday monetary policy meeting, where the central bank announced a 0.25 percentage point cut in interest rates, lowering its benchmark rate to a range of 4.25% to 4.5%.</p>
<p>Despite the widely expected rate cut, market participants focused more on the bank’s approach to monetary policy in 2025. The Fed, however, delivered surprisingly hawkish messages for the coming year.</p>
<p>The Fed projects only two quarter-point rate cuts in 2025, a change from previous projections, where four cuts were anticipated. The Fed&#8217;s cautious outlook is influenced by persistent inflation and a robust economy, leading to a more gradual approach to monetary easing.</p>
<p>Fed Chair Jerome Powell stated that the Fed is committed to achieving its target inflation at 2%. The November inflation rate in the US rose to 2.7%, up from 2.6% in October, which matched forecasts but remains above the bank’s goal.</p>
<p>Inflation is still elevated and above the bank’s goal despite economic activity continuing to expand, which prompts the Fed to carefully assess incoming economic data and risks before making further adjustments.</p>
<p>Not only that, the incoming administration of President-elect Donald Trump, sparks widespread concerns about accelerating inflation, though Trump’s proposed economic policies are kept unknown as of now.</p>
<p>Global markets reacted negatively to the Fed&#8217;s communication. Stock markets, in the meantime, crashed harder. Major indices suffered losses, with the S&amp;P 500 falling approximately 3%, the Dow Jones Industrial Average dropping around 100 points, and the Nasdaq Composite declining by about 3.6%.</p>
<p>Over $1 trillion was wiped out from the stock markets following the Fed’s policy meeting. Big falls may impact the FED, but inflation is an issue no matter what.</p>
<p>Bitcoin&#8217;s price quickly declined below $100,000, dropping to around $98,760 at one point during Powell&#8217;s remarks, before recovering slightly later. Yet the Crypto Fear and Greed Index, which gauges the overall sentiment of the cryptocurrency market, still sticks in the greed zone post-FOMC meeting.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blockonomi.com/bitcoins-fall-below-100k-sparks-renewed-buy-the-dip-discussions-santiment/">Bitcoin&#8217;s Fall Below $100k Sparks Renewed &#8216;Buy the Dip&#8217; Discussions: Santiment</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blockonomi.com">Blockonomi</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">108681</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bitcoin (BTC) Market Update: $700M in Liquidations as Price Drops Below Key Level</title>
		<link>https://blockonomi.com/bitcoin-btc-market-update-700m-in-liquidations-as-price-drops-below-key-level/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oliver Dale]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 09:54:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blockonomi.com/?p=108597</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>TLDR Bitcoin dropped below $100,000, triggering $700 million in liquidations across crypto futures markets, with XRP and DOGE seeing unusually high losses of around 5.5% The decline followed Fed Chair Powell&#8217;s comments that the central bank cannot legally own Bitcoin, responding to Trump&#8217;s campaign promise about strategic reserves The crypto market slide occurred after the [...]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blockonomi.com/bitcoin-btc-market-update-700m-in-liquidations-as-price-drops-below-key-level/">Bitcoin (BTC) Market Update: $700M in Liquidations as Price Drops Below Key Level</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blockonomi.com">Blockonomi</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>TLDR</h2>
<ul>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Bitcoin dropped below $100,000, triggering $700 million in liquidations across crypto futures markets, with XRP and DOGE seeing unusually high losses of around 5.5%</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">The decline followed Fed Chair Powell&#8217;s comments that the central bank cannot legally own Bitcoin, responding to Trump&#8217;s campaign promise about strategic reserves</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">The crypto market slide occurred after the Federal Reserve indicated potential rate cuts in 2025</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Chainlink (LINK) experienced the steepest decline at 10%, despite recent gains from a $2 million purchase by World Liberty Financial</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Market analysts are divided, with some seeing this as a potential local top while others maintain bullish outlook for 2025</li>
</ul>
<hr />
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words"><a href="https://www.coindesk.com/markets/2024/12/19/bitcoins-nosedive-to-under-100-k-shaves-700-m-crypto-longs-xrp-drops-5">Bitcoin dropped below the $100,000 mark during late U.S. trading hours on Wednesday,</a> triggering a wave of liquidations across cryptocurrency markets and leading to substantial losses for leveraged traders.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The price movement came in response to Federal Reserve Chair Jerome Powell&#8217;s statements during a post-FOMC press conference, where he addressed questions about cryptocurrency holdings and potential rate cuts in 2025.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Data from market tracking platforms showed that the price decline resulted in more than $700 million worth of liquidations in futures contracts across major cryptocurrencies. The market reaction was particularly notable in the altcoin sector, where smaller tokens experienced larger percentage drops than market leaders.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words"><a href="https://moneycheck.com/best-xrp-casinos/">XRP</a> and <a href="https://moneycheck.com/best-doge-casinos/">Dogecoin</a> futures markets recorded unusually high liquidation volumes, with both cryptocurrencies falling approximately 5.5% during the sell-off. This marked a departure from typical market behavior, where Bitcoin and Ethereum futures usually account for the majority of liquidation events.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The catalyst for the market movement appeared to be Powell&#8217;s response to questions about President-elect Donald Trump&#8217;s campaign promises regarding <a href="https://moneycheck.com/best-bitcoin-casinos/">Bitcoin</a> strategic reserves. Powell stated clearly that under current regulations, the Federal Reserve is not permitted to own Bitcoin.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">&#8220;That&#8217;s the kind of thing that Congress should consider, but we are not looking for a law change,&#8221; Powell explained during the press conference. This statement appeared to dampen market enthusiasm that had built up following Trump&#8217;s July campaign statement about maintaining government Bitcoin holdings.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Chainlink&#8217;s LINK token emerged as the day&#8217;s biggest loser, dropping 10% and erasing recent gains that had followed World Liberty Financial&#8217;s $2 million token purchase. The sharp decline highlighted the volatile nature of smaller market cap cryptocurrencies during broader market corrections.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Market data indicated that BNB Chain&#8217;s BNB token and Ethereum both declined by approximately 2.5%, showing more resilience than their smaller counterparts during the market turbulence.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Trading volumes spiked during the sell-off, with exchanges reporting increased activity across spot and derivatives markets. The high volume suggested active participation from both retail and institutional traders during the price movement.</p>
<figure id="attachment_108571" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-108571" style="width: 847px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-108571" src="https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-19-at-09-10-46-Bitcoin-Price-BTC-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko.png" alt="Bitcoin Price on CoinGecko" width="847" height="632" srcset="https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-19-at-09-10-46-Bitcoin-Price-BTC-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko.png 847w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-19-at-09-10-46-Bitcoin-Price-BTC-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-300x224.png 300w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-19-at-09-10-46-Bitcoin-Price-BTC-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-768x573.png 768w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-19-at-09-10-46-Bitcoin-Price-BTC-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-50x37.png 50w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-19-at-09-10-46-Bitcoin-Price-BTC-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-150x112.png 150w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-19-at-09-10-46-Bitcoin-Price-BTC-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-450x336.png 450w" sizes="(max-width: 847px) 100vw, 847px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-108571" class="wp-caption-text">Bitcoin Price on <a href="https://www.coingecko.com/en/coins/bitcoin">CoinGecko</a></figcaption></figure>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The Federal Reserve&#8217;s hints at potential rate cuts in 2025 would typically be considered positive news for cryptocurrency markets, but Powell&#8217;s specific comments about Bitcoin holdings appeared to overshadow the broader monetary policy outlook.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Nick Ruck, director at LVRG Research, shared his analysis via Telegram:</p>
<blockquote>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">&#8220;Crypto markets may have entered a peak if a U.S. Bitcoin strategic reserve is no longer in play, as this promise helped to fuel the recent months&#8217; rally to new all-time highs.&#8221;</p>
</blockquote>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Ruck also noted that while interest rate cuts typically generate positive market reactions, the market&#8217;s focus remained fixed on Powell&#8217;s comments about continued inflation concerns throughout the next year.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">However, not all market participants viewed the correction as a longer-term concern. Singapore-based QCP Capital maintained an optimistic outlook in their Thursday broadcast message, advising traders: &#8220;Don&#8217;t get shaken out of your positions if a drop occurs.&#8221;</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The trading firm pointed to potential positive catalysts in 2025, particularly citing the possibility of a Trump presidency as a factor that could benefit cryptocurrency markets.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Technical analysts noted that the $100,000 level had served as a psychological barrier for Bitcoin, and its breach triggered automated selling pressure from trading algorithms and stop-loss orders.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The liquidation cascade affected leveraged positions across multiple exchanges, with data showing that long positions were hit particularly hard during the market movement.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Trading activity remained elevated in Asian market hours as traders adjusted their positions and assessed the market impact of Powell&#8217;s statements.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blockonomi.com/bitcoin-btc-market-update-700m-in-liquidations-as-price-drops-below-key-level/">Bitcoin (BTC) Market Update: $700M in Liquidations as Price Drops Below Key Level</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blockonomi.com">Blockonomi</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">108597</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bitcoin (BTC) Makes History with 20% Drop in Exchange Reserves as Price Tops $104K</title>
		<link>https://blockonomi.com/bitcoin-btc-makes-history-with-20-drop-in-exchange-reserves-as-price-tops-104k/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oliver Dale]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 09:45:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blockonomi.com/?p=108592</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>TLDR Bitcoin exchange reserves have dropped to a historic low of 2.4 million BTC, down from 3 million at the start of 2024 The price has risen from $40,000 to over $104,000 in 2024, with major gains in November Institutional investors are increasingly adopting long-term holding strategies, removing BTC from exchanges The Coinbase Premium Index [...]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blockonomi.com/bitcoin-btc-makes-history-with-20-drop-in-exchange-reserves-as-price-tops-104k/">Bitcoin (BTC) Makes History with 20% Drop in Exchange Reserves as Price Tops $104K</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blockonomi.com">Blockonomi</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>TLDR</h2>
<ul>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Bitcoin exchange reserves have dropped to a historic low of 2.4 million BTC, down from 3 million at the start of 2024</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">The price has risen from $40,000 to over $104,000 in 2024, with major gains in November</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Institutional investors are increasingly adopting long-term holding strategies, removing BTC from exchanges</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">The Coinbase Premium Index shows declining US-based demand despite recent price increases</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Current supply shock conditions could support further price appreciation into 2025</li>
</ul>
<hr />
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The cryptocurrency market is witnessing a remarkable development as Bitcoin exchange reserves have plummeted to their lowest level ever recorded.<a href="https://cryptoquant.com/insights/quicktake/6762c86212a32e1b223f7f14-Historic-Drop-in-Bitcoin-Reserves-Are-New-Records-on-the-Horizon"> Data from CryptoQuant</a> reveals that Bitcoin holdings on exchanges have dropped to 2.4 million BTC, marking a substantial decrease from the 3 million BTC observed at the beginning of 2024.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words"><a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/bitcoin-news/bitcoin-exchange-reserves-hit-record-low-could-120k-be-on-the-horizon/">This dramatic reduction in exchange reserves comes as Bitcoin&#8217;s price has shown exceptional strength,</a> climbing from approximately $40,000 at the start of the year to breaking through the $104,000 barrier in recent trading sessions.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The declining exchange reserves reflect a clear shift in investor behavior, particularly among institutional players. These large-scale investors are increasingly embracing a &#8220;hodl&#8221; strategy, choosing to move their Bitcoin holdings off exchanges for longer-term storage solutions.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Market analysts point to this behavior as evidence of growing confidence in Bitcoin&#8217;s future prospects. The removal of Bitcoin from exchanges effectively reduces the available supply for trading, creating potential upward pressure on prices.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">CryptoQuant analyst Kripto Baykus has been closely monitoring these developments. According to their analysis, the steady decline in exchange reserves throughout 2024 has been a key factor supporting Bitcoin&#8217;s price appreciation.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The November price surge has been particularly noteworthy, with Bitcoin breaking through multiple psychological barriers before establishing new all-time highs above $104,000. This upward momentum has coincided with the continuing drain of Bitcoin from exchange wallets.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Technical analysts suggest that the combination of reduced supply and sustained demand could create conditions for further price appreciation. The current market dynamics appear to be setting up what many describe as a &#8220;supply shock&#8221; scenario.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">However, recent data from the Coinbase Premium Index, analyzed by CryptoQuant&#8217;s Yonsei Dent, presents a more nuanced picture of market demand. The index, which tracks activity on one of North America&#8217;s largest exchanges, has shown a decline despite Bitcoin&#8217;s price rising from $94,000 to $106,000 over the past two weeks.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">This divergence suggests that the recent price rally may not be primarily driven by US-based demand, adding an element of complexity to the market outlook. The declining Coinbase premium during a period of price appreciation has raised questions about the geographic distribution of buying pressure.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The movement of Bitcoin off exchanges continues a trend that began earlier in the year. Institutional investors have shown a clear preference for self-custody or institutional-grade custody solutions rather than keeping their holdings on exchanges.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Data shows that the rate of<a href="https://moneycheck.com/best-bitcoin-casinos/"> Bitcoin</a> leaving exchanges has accelerated in recent months, with the total reduction reaching 600,000 BTC since January 2024. This represents a substantial portion of the total circulating supply being moved into longer-term storage.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Market observers note that this behavior typically indicates strong conviction among holders, as moving Bitcoin off exchanges suggests a decreased intention to sell in the near term.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The impact of reduced exchange reserves is particularly notable given Bitcoin&#8217;s fixed supply cap of 21 million coins. With fewer coins available for trading, any increase in buying pressure could have a magnified effect on price.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Trading volumes across major exchanges have remained robust during this period, indicating that the market continues to function efficiently despite the reduced available supply. This suggests that the current price levels are being supported by genuine market activity rather than artificial constraints.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The latest data shows exchange outflows continuing at a steady pace, with no immediate signs of reversal in this trend. The total amount of Bitcoin held on exchanges now represents less than 12% of the total circulating supply.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blockonomi.com/bitcoin-btc-makes-history-with-20-drop-in-exchange-reserves-as-price-tops-104k/">Bitcoin (BTC) Makes History with 20% Drop in Exchange Reserves as Price Tops $104K</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blockonomi.com">Blockonomi</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">108592</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bitcoin (BTC) Price Target of $200,000 Supported by Multiple Technical Indicators</title>
		<link>https://blockonomi.com/bitcoin-btc-price-target-of-200000-supported-by-multiple-technical-indicators/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oliver Dale]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 09:12:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blockonomi.com/?p=108570</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>TLDR Bitcoin projected to reach $200,000 by mid-2025 according to Bitfinex analysis, with technical indicators showing continued bullish momentum Institutional inflows through ETFs expected to keep market corrections mild, with US spot ETFs now holding more BTC than Satoshi Nakamoto&#8217;s wallet Previous post-halving cycles showed decreasing correction sizes (33.2% in 2017 vs 27.1% in 2020) [...]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blockonomi.com/bitcoin-btc-price-target-of-200000-supported-by-multiple-technical-indicators/">Bitcoin (BTC) Price Target of $200,000 Supported by Multiple Technical Indicators</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blockonomi.com">Blockonomi</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>TLDR</h2>
<ul>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Bitcoin projected to reach $200,000 by mid-2025 according to Bitfinex analysis, with technical indicators showing continued bullish momentum</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Institutional inflows through ETFs expected to keep market corrections mild, with US spot ETFs now holding more BTC than Satoshi Nakamoto&#8217;s wallet</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Previous post-halving cycles showed decreasing correction sizes (33.2% in 2017 vs 27.1% in 2020)</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Potential US strategic Bitcoin reserve could drive prices even higher, with some experts projecting $500,000</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Japan considering creation of its own strategic BTC reserve, suggesting growing national interest in Bitcoin holdings</li>
</ul>
<hr />
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Bitcoin&#8217;s meteoric rise continues to capture market attention as new analysis suggests the leading cryptocurrency could reach $200,000 by mid-2025. <a href="https://blog.bitfinex.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Bitfinex-Alpha-135.pdf">A comprehensive report from cryptocurrency exchange Bitfinex</a>, released on December 17, outlines several factors supporting this bullish prediction.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words"><a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/bitcoin-news/bitcoin-may-surge-to-200000-by-mid-2025-amid-mild-price-pullbacks-report/">The cryptocurrency recently achieved a major milestone by crossing the $100,000 mark,</a> pushing its market capitalization above $2 trillion. This achievement, while impressive, may be just the beginning according to market analysts who see strong fundamentals supporting continued growth.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Technical indicators paint a positive picture for Bitcoin&#8217;s future price movement. The market value to realized value (MVRV) ratio, which helps determine if Bitcoin is over or undervalued, suggests the market remains in a healthy state. Additionally, the net unrealized profit/loss (NUPL) metric indicates there&#8217;s still room for growth before reaching levels typically associated with market peaks.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Historical data shows that years following Bitcoin halving events have consistently produced the strongest rallies. The Bitfinex report suggests that while the explosive growth seen in previous cycles might moderate, the cryptocurrency still has substantial upside potential under favorable market conditions.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Institutional investment has emerged as a key driver of Bitcoin&#8217;s price stability. US spot ETFs have accumulated impressive holdings, now surpassing the amount of Bitcoin held in Satoshi Nakamoto&#8217;s wallet. This steady institutional adoption is expected to continue, providing a strong foundation for future price growth.</p>
<figure id="attachment_108571" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-108571" style="width: 847px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-108571" src="https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-19-at-09-10-46-Bitcoin-Price-BTC-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko.png" alt="Bitcoin Price on CoinGecko" width="847" height="632" srcset="https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-19-at-09-10-46-Bitcoin-Price-BTC-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko.png 847w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-19-at-09-10-46-Bitcoin-Price-BTC-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-300x224.png 300w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-19-at-09-10-46-Bitcoin-Price-BTC-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-768x573.png 768w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-19-at-09-10-46-Bitcoin-Price-BTC-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-50x37.png 50w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-19-at-09-10-46-Bitcoin-Price-BTC-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-150x112.png 150w, https://blockonomi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-19-at-09-10-46-Bitcoin-Price-BTC-Live-Price-Chart-Market-Cap-News-Today-CoinGecko-450x336.png 450w" sizes="(max-width: 847px) 100vw, 847px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-108571" class="wp-caption-text">Bitcoin Price on <a href="https://www.coingecko.com/en/coins/bitcoin">CoinGecko</a></figcaption></figure>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The report projects a minimum price estimate of $145,000 by mid-2025, with potential to reach $200,000 if market conditions remain favorable. These projections are supported by analysis of previous market cycles and current trading patterns.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Post-halving price corrections have shown a decreasing trend over time. The 2017 cycle saw a maximum correction of 33.2%, while the 2020 cycle experienced a smaller 27.1% pullback. This pattern suggests increasing market maturity and stability.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Adding to the bullish outlook is the growing discussion around national Bitcoin reserves. The concept of a US strategic Bitcoin reserve has gained traction, with experts suggesting such a development could push prices even higher. Blockstream CEO Adam Back believes this scenario could drive Bitcoin into seven-figure territory.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Matt Hougan, Chief Investment Officer at Bitwise, has suggested that a US strategic Bitcoin reserve could propel the asset&#8217;s price to $500,000. The reasoning behind this projection stems from the likelihood that other nations would follow suit, creating increased demand for Bitcoin.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Interest in national <a href="https://moneycheck.com/best-bitcoin-casinos/">Bitcoin</a> reserves isn&#8217;t limited to the United States. Japanese Member of Parliament Satoshi Hamada has proposed the creation of a Japanese strategic Bitcoin reserve, indicating growing institutional interest at the national level.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Market analysts note that any price corrections during Q1 2025 are expected to be mild and short-lived, thanks to sustained institutional investment. This represents a departure from historical patterns of high volatility.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The combination of technical indicators, institutional adoption, and potential national reserve creation presents a compelling case for Bitcoin&#8217;s continued price appreciation. These factors suggest a more stable and mature market environment.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Current trading data shows Bitcoin at $103,953, representing a 3.7% decrease over the past 24 hours. Despite this short-term fluctuation, the overall market structure remains robust.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The report emphasizes that while returns might not match the explosive growth of earlier cycles, the market shows signs of increased stability and sustained growth potential. This maturation process suggests a more predictable and less volatile price trajectory.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The alignment of technical indicators, institutional involvement, and potential government adoption creates a unique market environment that supports the possibility of reaching new all-time highs in the coming years.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blockonomi.com/bitcoin-btc-price-target-of-200000-supported-by-multiple-technical-indicators/">Bitcoin (BTC) Price Target of $200,000 Supported by Multiple Technical Indicators</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blockonomi.com">Blockonomi</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">108570</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>BlackRock&#8217;s Bitcoin ETF Reaches $36 Billion in Record-Breaking Inflows</title>
		<link>https://blockonomi.com/blackrocks-bitcoin-etf-reaches-36-billion-in-record-breaking-inflows/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oliver Dale]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 11:20:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blockonomi.com/?p=108532</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>TLDR BlackRock&#8217;s IBIT Bitcoin ETF secured over $36.3 billion in net flows in 11 months, becoming the most successful ETF launch in a decade IBIT outperformed approximately 2,850 ETFs launched since 2014 The fund achieved a record single-day inflow of over $1.1 billion Total Bitcoin ETF assets under management reached $130 billion, surpassing gold ETFs [...]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blockonomi.com/blackrocks-bitcoin-etf-reaches-36-billion-in-record-breaking-inflows/">BlackRock&#8217;s Bitcoin ETF Reaches $36 Billion in Record-Breaking Inflows</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blockonomi.com">Blockonomi</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>TLDR</h2>
<ul>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">BlackRock&#8217;s IBIT Bitcoin ETF secured over $36.3 billion in net flows in 11 months, becoming the most successful ETF launch in a decade</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">IBIT outperformed approximately 2,850 ETFs launched since 2014</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">The fund achieved a record single-day inflow of over $1.1 billion</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Total Bitcoin ETF assets under management reached $130 billion, surpassing gold ETFs</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Despite GBTC&#8217;s $21 billion outflows, spot Bitcoin ETFs secured over $36 billion in year-to-date flows</li>
</ul>
<hr />
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">BlackRock&#8217;s spot Bitcoin ETF (IBIT) has <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/blackrocks-ibit-becomes-decades-top-etf-for-inflows-surpassing-all-rivals/">emerged as the most successful ETF launch of the past decade, gathering more than $36.3 billion in net flows since its inception.</a> The fund, which began trading just 11 months ago, has surpassed approximately 2,850 other ETFs launched since 2014.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words"><a href="https://farside.co.uk/btc/">According to data from Farside Investors,</a> IBIT&#8217;s performance has exceeded all other US-traded spot Bitcoin ETFs. The fund&#8217;s success is particularly notable when compared to its closest competitor, Fidelity&#8217;s FBTC, which has accumulated $12.4 billion in inflows &#8211; less than half of IBIT&#8217;s total.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The ETF achieved another milestone by recording the highest single-day inflow among Bitcoin ETFs, bringing in over $1.1 billion in just 24 hours. This amount is more than double the previous record of $473.4 million, set by Fidelity&#8217;s FBTC.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">On December 16, 2024, IBIT added another $418.8 million to its impressive track record of positive net flows. This consistent growth has helped establish the fund as a dominant force in the ETF market.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The broader Bitcoin ETF market has shown remarkable strength, with total inflows exceeding $36 billion year-to-date. This achievement is particularly noteworthy considering it occurred despite Grayscale&#8217;s GBTC experiencing $21 billion in outflows following its conversion.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">With this inflow, I show IBIT is now the most successful ETF launch over past 10yrs…</p>
<p>Out of approx 2,850 ETFs.</p>
<p>In other words, IBIT has more *lifetime* inflows than any ETF launched since 2014.</p>
<p>Did this in just over 11mos. <a href="https://t.co/40xQ60JewL">https://t.co/40xQ60JewL</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Nate Geraci (@NateGeraci) <a href="https://twitter.com/NateGeraci/status/1868843555571351719?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 17, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The combined assets under management of US-traded Bitcoin ETFs, including futures and leveraged products, have reached $130 billion. This figure surpasses the $128 billion held in gold ETFs, as reported by Bloomberg senior ETF analyst Eric Balchunas.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Looking at spot Bitcoin ETFs alone, their total assets under management stand at nearly $117 billion after just 11 months of trading. This rapid growth has surprised many market observers, including Balchunas, who described the pace as &#8220;unreal.&#8221;</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">These ETF products have provided US-based institutional investors with a regulated method to gain exposure to cryptocurrencies, particularly Bitcoin and Ethereum. The structured investment vehicles have made it easier for traditional financial institutions to participate in the crypto market.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The success of these products has coincided with Bitcoin&#8217;s strong performance throughout the year. Bitfinex analysts have identified ETF adoption as one of the key factors that could alter Bitcoin&#8217;s traditional market cycles.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">BlackRock&#8217;s achievement with IBIT represents a major milestone in the mainstreaming of cryptocurrency investments. The fund&#8217;s record-breaking inflows demonstrate strong institutional demand for regulated crypto investment products.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The performance gap between IBIT and other <a href="https://moneycheck.com/best-bitcoin-casinos/">Bitcoin</a> ETFs highlights BlackRock&#8217;s strong position in the market. The firm&#8217;s established reputation and wide distribution network have likely contributed to its ability to attract substantial investments.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Monthly inflow patterns show consistent growth for IBIT, indicating sustained interest from investors rather than short-term speculation. This steady accumulation suggests a long-term investment approach from institutional participants.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The success of Bitcoin ETFs has occurred across multiple providers, though with varying degrees of market penetration. While BlackRock leads the pack, other major financial institutions have also captured substantial market share.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Market data indicates that the majority of IBIT&#8217;s inflows have come from institutional investors, showing strong professional interest in regulated crypto investment vehicles. This institutional adoption represents a shift from earlier years when crypto investments were dominated by retail investors.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The latest figures from December 2024 show continuing momentum for IBIT, with daily inflows remaining strong even after eleven months of trading.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blockonomi.com/blackrocks-bitcoin-etf-reaches-36-billion-in-record-breaking-inflows/">BlackRock&#8217;s Bitcoin ETF Reaches $36 Billion in Record-Breaking Inflows</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blockonomi.com">Blockonomi</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">108532</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Galaxy Digital Research Shows Bitcoin ETFs Outperforming Gold ETFs</title>
		<link>https://blockonomi.com/galaxy-digital-research-shows-bitcoin-etfs-outperforming-gold-etfs/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oliver Dale]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 10:48:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blockonomi.com/?p=108505</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>TLDR Bitcoin&#8217;s market cap has reached 14% of gold&#8217;s $17.8 trillion value, hitting a new all-time high relation to gold Bitcoin price reached $108,000 on Dec. 17, with its market cap now at $2.13 trillion Federal Reserve Chair Powell acknowledged Bitcoin as a &#8220;digital version&#8221; of gold while maintaining it&#8217;s a speculative asset Bitcoin ETFs [...]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blockonomi.com/galaxy-digital-research-shows-bitcoin-etfs-outperforming-gold-etfs/">Galaxy Digital Research Shows Bitcoin ETFs Outperforming Gold ETFs</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blockonomi.com">Blockonomi</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>TLDR</h2>
<ul>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Bitcoin&#8217;s market cap has reached 14% of gold&#8217;s $17.8 trillion value, hitting a new all-time high relation to gold</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Bitcoin price reached $108,000 on Dec. 17, with its market cap now at $2.13 trillion</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Federal Reserve Chair Powell acknowledged Bitcoin as a &#8220;digital version&#8221; of gold while maintaining it&#8217;s a speculative asset</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Bitcoin ETFs have surpassed gold ETFs in total assets under management ($129.25B vs $128.88B)</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Galaxy CEO Novogratz predicts Bitcoin will surpass gold&#8217;s market cap in 5-8 years</li>
</ul>
<hr />
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Bitcoin continues to break records in December 2024, reaching new heights in both its price and its relationship to gold. The cryptocurrency&#8217;s market capitalization has grown to 14% of gold&#8217;s $17.8 trillion value, marking a historic milestone in the asset&#8217;s evolution.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">On December 17, Bitcoin&#8217;s price surged to $108,000, pushing its total market capitalization to $2.13 trillion. This value now represents more than two-thirds of the gold held by central banks worldwide, which stands at $3.13 trillion.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The growing acceptance of Bitcoin in traditional finance circles has been highlighted by recent developments in the ETF market. Bitcoin ETFs have accumulated $129.25 billion in assets under management, exceeding gold ETFs which hold $128.88 billion. BlackRock&#8217;s iShares Bitcoin ETF (IBIT) has shown particularly strong performance compared to its gold counterpart, the iShares Gold ETF (IAU).</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words"><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/galaxy-ceo-predicts-bitcoin-market-cap-will-overtake-gold-in-5-to-8-years/">Alex Thorn, head of research at Galaxy, presented data showing Bitcoin&#8217;s increasing share of gold&#8217;s market capitalization.</a> His analysis included a chart demonstrating the accelerating growth pattern of Bitcoin relative to the precious metal.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Mike Novogratz, founder and CEO of Galaxy Digital, has made a bold prediction based on these trends. He believes Bitcoin&#8217;s total market value could match and eventually exceed that of gold within the next five to eight years.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The cryptocurrency&#8217;s rise comes as the U.S. Federal Reserve considers potential rate cuts. This monetary policy backdrop has created favorable conditions for Bitcoin&#8217;s growth, as investors seek alternative stores of value.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Federal Reserve Chair Jerome Powell has contributed to the ongoing discussion about Bitcoin&#8217;s role in the financial system. In recent statements, Powell acknowledged Bitcoin as a &#8220;digital version&#8221; of gold, marking a shift in how top financial officials view the cryptocurrency.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">However, Powell maintained a measured stance, describing <a href="https://moneycheck.com/best-bitcoin-casinos/">Bitcoin</a> as a speculative asset. He emphasized that while Bitcoin may share some characteristics with gold, it does not serve the same functions as traditional sovereign currencies like the U.S. dollar.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The Fed Chair pointed out that Bitcoin&#8217;s primary appeal remains narrow in scope. He noted that the cryptocurrency has not become widely used for everyday payments or as a medium of exchange, distinguishing it from conventional currencies.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The institutional investment landscape for Bitcoin continues to evolve. Traditional financial firms are increasingly offering Bitcoin-related products and services to meet growing client demand.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Data shows that Bitcoin&#8217;s market presence has grown steadily throughout 2024. The cryptocurrency&#8217;s value now exceeds important benchmarks that were previously considered unreachable by many market observers.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The relationship between Bitcoin and gold has become a key metric for measuring the cryptocurrency&#8217;s growth. As Bitcoin&#8217;s market share relative to gold increases, it represents a shift in how investors view digital assets.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Trading volumes for Bitcoin have remained robust, indicating sustained interest from both retail and institutional investors. Market data shows consistent participation across various trading venues and investment products.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Price discovery for Bitcoin has become more efficient as market infrastructure continues to develop. The increased presence of regulated venues and professional traders has contributed to more stable and liquid markets.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Recent market activity suggests that Bitcoin&#8217;s growth trajectory may continue as more investors gain exposure to the asset class. Trading patterns indicate steady accumulation by both long-term holders and new market participants.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blockonomi.com/galaxy-digital-research-shows-bitcoin-etfs-outperforming-gold-etfs/">Galaxy Digital Research Shows Bitcoin ETFs Outperforming Gold ETFs</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blockonomi.com">Blockonomi</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">108505</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>US Bitcoin Policy Takes Shape: National Reserve Plan and State Treasury Bills</title>
		<link>https://blockonomi.com/us-bitcoin-policy-takes-shape-national-reserve-plan-and-state-treasury-bills/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oliver Dale]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 10:12:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blockonomi.com/?p=108499</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>TLDR Wyoming Senator Lummis declares 2025 crucial for Bitcoin with David Sacks as &#8220;Crypto Czar&#8221; Lummis introduces BITCOIN Act proposing 1 million BTC national reserve over 5 years Trump administration promises to make US the &#8220;crypto capital&#8221; with clear regulatory framework US government currently holds $21 billion in Bitcoin from seized assets Multiple states including [...]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blockonomi.com/us-bitcoin-policy-takes-shape-national-reserve-plan-and-state-treasury-bills/">US Bitcoin Policy Takes Shape: National Reserve Plan and State Treasury Bills</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blockonomi.com">Blockonomi</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>TLDR</h2>
<ul>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Wyoming Senator Lummis declares 2025 crucial for Bitcoin with David Sacks as &#8220;Crypto Czar&#8221;</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Lummis introduces BITCOIN Act proposing 1 million BTC national reserve over 5 years</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Trump administration promises to make US the &#8220;crypto capital&#8221; with clear regulatory framework</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">US government currently holds $21 billion in Bitcoin from seized assets</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Multiple states including Ohio, Pennsylvania, and Texas pursuing Bitcoin treasury initiatives</li>
</ul>
<hr />
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words"><a href="https://decrypt.co/297230/wyoming-senator-cynthia-lummis-2025-will-be-the-year-for-bitcoin-and-digital-assets">Wyoming Senator Cynthia Lummis has unveiled ambitious plans to establish a national Bitcoin reserve, marking a potential turning point in U.S. cryptocurrency policy.</a> The initiative comes as multiple states pursue their own Bitcoin treasury programs, pointing to growing mainstream acceptance of digital assets at various levels of government.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Lummis, often called the &#8220;Bitcoin Senator,&#8221; recently introduced the Boosting Innovation, Technology, and Competitiveness Through Optimized Investment Nationwide (BITCOIN) Act of 2024. The legislation proposes creating a Strategic Bitcoin Reserve with the goal of acquiring 1 million Bitcoin over five years, representing 5% of the total supply.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The proposed reserve would operate through a network of secure storage vaults and purchase programs. Rather than creating new debt, the initiative would be funded by reallocating existing Federal Reserve assets, including bonds and gold.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The U.S. government already holds an estimated $21 billion in Bitcoin, according to Arkham Intelligence data. These holdings, primarily from seized criminal assets, could potentially be integrated into the strategic reserve if the legislation passes.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">President-elect Donald Trump has appointed venture capitalist David Sacks as &#8220;Crypto Czar&#8221; to oversee artificial intelligence and crypto policy initiatives. Trump&#8217;s administration has promised to protect domestic crypto mining interests and develop clear regulations to help the industry grow.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Sacks will work on creating a legal framework to provide the crypto industry with regulatory clarity, addressing a long-standing concern among cryptocurrency businesses operating in the United States.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The BITCOIN Act includes a mandatory 20-year holding period for the reserve assets, emphasizing a long-term commitment to Bitcoin as a strategic resource. During a speech at the Bitcoin conference in Nashville, Lummis suggested the reserve could help reduce the national debt by half before 2045.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">At the state level, Ohio Representative Derek Merrin has introduced legislation that would allow the state treasury to invest public funds in Bitcoin. The bill represents one of several state-level initiatives to integrate cryptocurrency into government finance.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Pennsylvania has taken similar steps, with Representative Mike Cabell proposing legislation to allocate up to 10% of the state&#8217;s treasury reserves to Bitcoin. The measure is positioned as a strategy to protect against inflation.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Texas has proposed its own approach to Bitcoin adoption, with plans to fund a reserve through donations and allow <a href="https://moneycheck.com/best-bitcoin-casinos/">Bitcoin</a> payments for taxes and fees. This move aligns with the state&#8217;s growing reputation as a hub for cryptocurrency mining operations.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The timing of these initiatives coincides with Bitcoin reaching new price milestones, recently surpassing $100,000 for the first time. This price movement has attracted increased attention from government officials and institutional investors.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Trump&#8217;s incoming administration will include a reshuffle of key government positions, including a new SEC chair, potentially creating a more favorable environment for cryptocurrency regulation and adoption.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Senator Lummis has expressed optimism about 2025 being a pivotal year for Bitcoin and digital assets, citing the convergence of proposed policies and new government appointments. Her social media posts suggest close collaboration with Sacks on comprehensive digital asset legislation.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The federal government&#8217;s existing Bitcoin holdings from seized assets demonstrate the scale of cryptocurrency&#8217;s presence in federal finances, even before the proposed strategic reserve. These holdings could provide a foundation for expanded government involvement in the digital asset space.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">State-level initiatives represent a parallel track of Bitcoin adoption, with different approaches emerging across various jurisdictions. These efforts range from direct investment proposals to tax payment programs, showing diverse strategies for cryptocurrency integration.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blockonomi.com/us-bitcoin-policy-takes-shape-national-reserve-plan-and-state-treasury-bills/">US Bitcoin Policy Takes Shape: National Reserve Plan and State Treasury Bills</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blockonomi.com">Blockonomi</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">108499</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
